■
本字幕由网络爱好者联盟原创翻译
在保留译者名单的前提下任何人不需要经得我们的同意
可用本字幕做任何用途因此所产生的后果由您自行承担
欢迎加入我们 www.ZiMuZu.pub
{\clip(201,214,201,216)\t(0,600,2,\clip(110,214,292,216))\t(4200,4800,2,\clip(201,214,201,216))}■
{\clip(80,216,392,216)\t(600,1000,2,\clip(80,192,392,240))\t(4200,4600,2,\clip(80,216,392,216))}翻\h译
青色桔子\h\h\h\hepsilonN\h\h\h\h甜甜的棉花糖\h\h\h\hypoqou
{\clip(201,214,201,216)\t(0,600,2,\clip(110,214,292,216))\t(4200,4800,2,\clip(201,214,201,216))}■
{\clip(80,216,392,216)\t(600,1000,2,\clip(80,192,392,240))\t(4200,4600,2,\clip(80,216,392,216))}翻\h译
东风冽\h\h\h\hcamillechezrenren\h\h\h\hJohn3069\h\h\h\hHanson-heyi幽灵王子
{\clip(201,214,201,216)\t(0,600,2,\clip(110,214,292,216))\t(4200,4800,2,\clip(201,214,201,216))}■
{\clip(110,216,292,216)\t(600,1000,2,\clip(110,192,292,240))\t(4200,4600,2,\clip(110,216,292,216))}校对\h&\h后期
我要头发不要校对\h\h\h\h你以为列
{\clip(62,224,336,224)\t(1000,1400,2,\clip(62,204,336,224))\t(7600,8000,\clip(62,224,336,224))}■
{\clip(62,224,336,224)\t(1000,1400,2,\clip(62,204,336,224))\t(7600,8000,\clip(62,224,336,224))}片头推广合作洽谈：请联系普罗米修斯邮箱 PLMXS2016@GmaiL.com
我只能摆出各种姿势
Gestures are all that I have.
我 在 雨 中 等 你
我无法说话
I have no words I can rely on,
我的舌头又长又平
because my tongue was designed long and flat
因此它无法作为一个可以帮助我
and is therefore an ineffective tool
发出抱怨的多音节声音的工具
for making complicated polysyllabic sounds.
所以我在这里
And that is why I'm here now,
就躺在我撒的这滩尿旁
waiting for Denny to come home...
等丹尼回家
lying in a puddle of my own making.
哟  恩佐
Yo, Enz!
恩佐
Enzo?
我从他的声音里听出了忧虑
I hear the worry in his voice.
怎么了  伙计
What happened, pal?
Enz
Oh, Enz.
我可以闻出他今天做了什么
I can smell the day on him.
机油  汽油还有烤鸡味
Motor oil and gasoline and roast chicken.
能起来吗  哥们
Can you get up. Bud?
我在这  哥们  我就在这
I'm here, buddy. I'm right here.
好的
Okay.
要是我能说话的话
If only I could speak...
我就会告诉他  别担心
I would tell him not to worry.
我曾在电视上看过一部蒙古的纪录片
I saw a documentary about Mongolia on TV once.
在蒙古  他们相信当一只狗
In Mongolia, they believe that when a dog
结束了它的狗生后
has finished living his lifetimes as a dog,
它就会转世成人
his next incarnation will be as a man.
我就在这  老兄
I'm right here, bud.
来吧
There he is.
我意识到这意味着我会失去
I realize this would mean losing
我所有的回忆和经历
all my memories, my experiences.
但是我有个主意
But I have a plan.
我要试着把我所知道的烙印进灵魂
I will try to imprint what I know on my soul,
深深地刻印我的生命里
carry it so deeply in the pockets of my existence
当我睁开双眼  看着我全新的双手时
that when I open my eyes and look down at my new hands,
我就会知道一切
I will already know.
来吧我的恩佐
There's my Enzo.
我会准备好的
I will be ready.
我会记住一切的
I will remember.
他从一群小狗的乱七八糟的爪子
He picked me out of a pile of pups,
和尾巴堆中选中了我
a tangled mass of paws and tails.
他把车停在他回家路上的一个农场里
He'd stopped at the farm on his way home
就在雅基马城的公路旁
from the speedway at Yakima.
雅基马城:美国华盛顿州
你好
Hey.
现在回想  我知道我与其他狗生而不同
Even back then, I knew I was different than other dogs.
我的灵魂更能感觉到  人性
My soul just felt more... human.
就这只吧
This one.
绝对是这只
Definitely this one.
-这一只最漂亮  -她老爱这么说
- The pick of the litter. - She always said that.
威尔先生  等一下
Mr. Well, just a minute now.
我们想留下这一只
We were thinking of keeping that one.
这老头也爱这么说
He always said that, too.
你好呀
Hey.
要多少钱
How much?
然后  我开始了我狗生的第一瞥
And so, I had my first glimpse at the rest of my life.
♪ 给我一片净土 ♪
♪ Give me peace on Earth ♪
bgm:Give Me Love--- Jeff Lynne
♪ 赐我光明  助我生而自由 ♪
♪ Give me light, give me life, keep me free from birth ♪
♪ 送我希望  助我负重前行 ♪
♪ Give me hope, help me cope with this heavy load ♪
♪ 试着接近  去触碰你 ♪
♪ Trying to, touch and reach you with, ♪
♪ 用我的真心与灵魂 ♪
♪ With heart and soul ♪
♪ 请抓紧我的手 ♪
♪ Please take hold of my hand, ♪
♪ 这样我就能理解你 ♪
♪ that I might understand you ♪
♪ 请你不要松手 ♪
♪ Won't you please oh won't you ♪
♪ 试着接近  去触碰你 ♪
♪ Trying to, touch and reach you ♪
♪ 送我希望  助我负重前行 ♪
♪ Help me cope with this heavy load ♪
♪ 用我的真心与灵魂 ♪
♪ With heart and soul ♪
托尼  丹尼来了
Tony! Denny's here.
稍等
Ah, just wait for it.
我都不知道你居然买了条小狗
I didn't know you were getting a puppy.
我也没想到
Neither did I.
在路边看到了标牌  然后我就被什么吸引了
Saw a sign on the road and, I don't know, something came over me.
这不是挺好的嘛  恩佐
Isn't that right, Enzo'?
恩佐  你是说像法拉利  真不错
"Enzo"? You mean like Ferrari? That's rad.
你没法照顾它  你基本不在家
You can't look after a dog. You're never home.
你可真是会毁气氛
Oh, you're gonna ruin the moment, aren't you?
我们最好的朋友  他要毁气氛了
Our best friend, he's gonna ruin the moment.
我会带着他坐车  他可以做我的幸运物
I'll take him on the road with me. He can be my good luck charm.
你会来看我们今晚的表演吗
Hey, you coming to our show tonight?
我们帮潜水嘲笑开场
We're opening for The Scoffs at The Dive.
不  他不行  他得照顾小狗狗
Oh, no, he can't. He's got a new puppy to look after.
看看  他已经带来好运了
See, he's good luck already.
我今早已经接到电话
I got the call this morning,
他们需要一个额外的车手
they need an extra driver.
好的  是的
Yeah, sure.
没错  我会给你留一张大门通行证
Yeah, I'll, uh, leave you a pass at the gate.
好吧  两张
Okay, two passes.
那家伙是谁来着
Who is this guy again?
没错
That's right.
我喜欢我的新家
I liked my new home.
就是少了点草  不过我觉得我可以帮帮忙
It only lacked for grass, but I figured I could make do.
恩佐不行
Enzo, no!
唐  我会打给你
Don, I got to call you back.
去吧
And... go ahead.
好的  老弟  现在可以放水了
Okay, bud, fire away.
丹尼似乎对我的厕所习惯有不一般的兴趣
Denny seemed unusually interested in my bathroom habits.
撒呀  不要害羞
Go on. Go ahead.
当然  你已经撒了
Of course, you did.
好的伙计
Okay, pal...
是时候睡觉了  明天可是赛车的大日子
it's time to turn in. Big day tomorrow at the race.
做个听话的好孩子
So just be a good boy.
睡一会好吗
Get some sleep, okay?
好吧
Okay.
行吧
All right.
好的
Okay.
当然啦  只要擦一点在
Of course. Just rub that in...
后来我学会了  这个叫做电视
I'd later learn it was called a television.
它能及时地教我了解更多的人类行为
And, in time, it would teach me much about human behavior.
但是在那晚  新世界的窗户就此打开
But that night, it felt like a window into a whole new world.
你喜欢这个是吗
Oh, you like that, huh?
喜欢吗  不对  应该说是我爱死了
Like it? No, I loved it.
右脚油门
Right foot on the gas.
轻松过弯
Ease into the turn.
更棒的是他还带我去赛车现场
And even better was when he took me to the race itself.
丹尼
Denny!
我的天
Oh. My God...
丹尼的公寓是我的家
Denny's apartment was home, but this...
但我觉得我真正属于这里
this was where I truly belonged.
这比我想象中还要令狗激动
It was more thrilling than I could've imagined.
感觉如何  恩佐
What do you think, Enzo?
我觉得这里是人间天堂
I thought it was heaven on earth.
能再说一次他的名字吗
What'd you say his name is again?
丹尼·斯威夫特  96号赛车
Denny Swift. Number 96 car.
他需要钱时
He teaches for me from time to time
会不时地充当我老师  但相信我
when he needs cash, but you trust me,
-他是一颗历经磨砺的钻石  -收到
- this kid's a diamond in the rough. - Copy that.
从赛车上传来的阵阵高温
The heat coming off the track,
令人屏息的速度  维修站员工们的精确度
the breathless speed and precision of the pit crew...
这一切都令我敬畏
I was in awe of it all.
他参加了一年的F3赛
He did a year in Formula Three.
被奇皮·西蒙的奥迪计划选中
Got picked up by Zip Simone's Audi program.
开始为自己挣得名声  但后来奇皮破产了
Started making a name for himself, but then Zippy went bankrupt.
于是他失去了他的座驾
Then he lost his ride.
离库
Clear!
你对开创你的专属队伍十分严肃
You really serious about starting your own team,
你的队员就在那里
there's your man right there.
在跑完一圈后他会开始感到不支
He's been down almost a full lap this whole stint.
这不关乎谁踩油门更重
It's not about who's got the heavier foot.
而是关乎赛车的感觉
It's about the feel.
丹尼是第一个叫人换雨胎的人
Denny was the first to make the call to switch to rain tires.
来这儿
Step over here.
看好了
Hey. Watch this.
在我的赛车生涯中
In all my years of racing,
我从未见过丹尼这样雨中飙车的
I've never seen anyone like Denny in the wet.
使我想起他们描述塞纳的话
Reminds me what they used to say about Senna,
艾尔顿·塞纳:被称为历来一级方程式赛车手中最伟大的车手之一
他从雨中过  滴雨不沾身
"When it rains, it doesn't rain on him."
然后每当他赢了的时候
And when he won...
恩佐
Enzo!
我总觉得我见证了一场真正伟大的胜利
I felt like I'd witnessed true greatness.
好耶
Yeah!
第一场赛事
First race, huh?
感觉如何  老兄  喜欢吗
What'd you think, boy? You like it?
你喜欢吗
Did you like it?
孩子  能和你谈谈吗
Hey, kid, you got a minute?
我想要你见见肖恩·怀特
I want you to meet Sean Wright.
-你好  -我是丹尼·斯威夫特
- Hey. - Denny Swift.
他卖掉了他的科技公司  拿到了一大笔钱
He sold his tech company for some obscene amount of money
现在他又要把它耗费在GT赛车5系列上
and now he's determined to waste it all racing GT5.
GT:制造标准比得上赛车的高级跑车
好的  我觉得我有读到过你的故事
Yeah, I think I've read about you.
今天还有几场胜利等着你
That was some win today.
你觉得你能为了他赛这场车吗
You think you could drive that way for him?
我试试吧
Try me.
我刚出生第一年的记忆已经有些模糊不清了
My first year went by in a blur.
停下  让我瞧瞧
Wait. Let me see.
我意识到没有哪只狗会有一个完美的童年
I realize nobody has a perfect childhood,
但我认为我的已经接近完美了
but I'd contend that mine came fairly close.
丹尼开始专门帮怀特赛车
Denny began racing for Wright full-time
只要有可能他都会把我带上
and took me with him whenever he could,
就像我是维修站的一位四腿成员
like a four-legged member of the pit crew.
-恩佐你还好吗  -感觉狗生已到达了高潮
- Hey, Enz, you good? - I was better than good.
去吧  离库
Go! Clear!
把它叫做命运  或是幸运
Call it fate, call it luck.
我只知道我注定要做他的狗
All I knew was I was meant to be his dog.
丹尼总是说最好的赛车手只需专注于现在
Denny always said the best drivers focus only on the present.
不必沉溺在过去  也从不寄希于将来
Never dwelling on the past, never committing to the future.
冲呀
Go get it!
事后总需要反思
Reflection must come at a later time.
这也是为什么赛车手们要用车载摄像头
Which is why drivers compulsively record
强制记录他们的一举一动
their every move with their in-car cameras.
我转弯早了点
I got to turn earlier.
可以把这个弯过得更漂亮
Get a better run on that corner.
我在与他的合作中学到了平衡
I teamed so much from him about balance,
预判  耐心
anticipation, patience.
车随眼动  恩佐
Car goes where your eyes go, Enz.
我会幻想  某天我也能够赛车
And I would fantasize that one day I, too, might actually race.
为今天的巨大成功喝彩
Congratulations on a spectacular win today.
不管怎么看  这一场并不容易
Not an easy race, by any stretch.
我是一个冒险之徒
Well, you know, I'm a risk taker.
伙计  那场胜利都是因为你
Man, that win was all you.
这家伙却一次也没提到你
This guy hasn't even mentioned you once.
你为他铺平了道路  丹尼
You're way too good for this guy, Denny.
是时候开始找你自己的赞助商了
You got to start getting your own sponsors.
是啊  也许吧
Yeah, maybe.
我的车手把我视作他们的头儿
My drivers look to me as their leader
我觉得
and I think that...
小丑下场  该换水手上了
Turn this clown off. Put on the Mariners.
我听丹尼重复着一句老话
There's an old saying I'd often hear Denny repeat,
没有哪场比赛会在第一个弯道那里获胜
"No race was ever won in the first corner,
但许多人却会在那里输掉
but many have been lost there."
只有你和我  恩佐
Just you and me, Enz.
总是你和我
Always you and me.
然后加速通过
And then accelerating through.
比赛对于我们来说重于一切
Nothing was more important to us than racing.
我知道丹尼离达到他
I knew it was only a matter of time
在欧洲的F1目标没有多久了
before Denny reached his goal of racing Formula One in Europe.
过来
Come on!
全世界都会像我这样看着他
And the whole world would see him the way I did.
好孩子
Good boy.
他在哪都被粉丝崇拜着
He'd be adored by fans everywhere.
他的胜利成为传奇
His victories the stuff of legend.
他的名字被铭刻在
His name inscribed alongside
我们所知体育赛事中的最好一面上
the very best our sport has ever known.
但此时此刻  他是独属于我的第一名
But for now, he was my champion alone.
然后  她出现了
And then she showed up.
-棒极了  -很好
- That was great. - Yeah.
-恩佐  这是伊芙  -嗨恩佐
- Enzo, this is Eve. - Hi, Enzo.
你好吗
How you doing?
我对伊芙的第一印象
My first impression of Eve
就像这空气中的气味一样复杂
was as complicated as the scents in the air.
我不太算是爱狗人士
I'm not really much of a dog person.
农产品  洗发水香味和性外激素的大杂烩
A mélange of produce, shampoo and pheromones.
好吧  他比一般狗通人性
Yeah, well, he's more person than dog.
丹尼显然被她的整洁打扮迷住了
Denny was cleary taken with her grooming.
要我猜  她大概每天都洗澡吧
She probably bathed every day, for all I knew.
他总是这样盯着别人看吗
Does he always stare at people like this?
假如他喜欢那个人的话
If he likes them.
所以  你是个厨师还是什么
So, are you a chef or something?
不  我给非母语者教英语课
No, I teach English as a second language,
我有个学生是泰国人
and one of my students is Thai,
她有次做了超好吃的咖喱
and she made this curry that was incredible.
-嘿  别这样  -但你好像得走了
- Hey. Come on. - But it looks like you have to go.
我不知道他中了什么邪
I don't know what's gotten into him. Hey!
那么  很高兴认识你
So, it was nice to meet you.
过来  快点  嘿  伊芙
Come here, come on! Hey, uh, Eve?
我  我有朋友是搞乐队的
My, uh, my friends, they play in a band
他们今晚  在尼莫酒吧有场表演
and they're playing a show at... at Nemo's tonight.
我想着  要是你没其他事的话
I thought, you know, it you didn't have plans...
"头部受伤"
"Head Injury"?
对  他们是西雅图第三流行的
Yeah, they're Seattle's third most popular
-声音花园的  -声音花园的致敬乐队
- Soundgarden... - "Soundgarden tribute band."
声音花园乐队  20世纪最有影响力的乐队之一
我是说  他们就这样讲的
I mean, according to them.
-听上去很有意思  -是吗
- That sounds like fun. - It does?
对  对  会很  会很有意思的
Yeah! Yeah, no, we'll, we'll make it fun.
-那好  到时候见  -好
- All right, I'll see you then. - Cool.
再见
Bye.
来吧
Come on.
我觉得你们刚刚酷毙了
Well, I thought you guys rocked.
你知道吗  麦克他都抓狂了
See, Mike? He was freaking out
因为我们唱"勺子哥"的时候跳了一段
because we skipped a verse on "Spoonman".
-是我们跳了一段吗  -好了
- Oh, we skipped a verse? - Okay, so,
想想他们从高中起就这么闹了
now imagine this all throughout high school.
所以你最喜欢哪首歌
So, which song was your favorite?
倒数第二首
The... second-to-last one.
有12分钟吉他独奏的那首吗
The one with the 12-minute guitar solo?
对  那就是最棒的地方
Yeah, that was the best part!
丹尼  娶了她吧
Denny, marry this girl.
你还要一瓶吗
Uh, do you want another?
不了谢谢  能给我杯水吗
Uh, no, thanks. Could I have some water?
-好嘞  麦克呢  -来一瓶
- Yeah, sure. Mike? - Yep.
-所以  你们刚认识  是吗  -对
- So, uh, you two just met, huh? - Yeah.
-然后呢  -兄弟
- And? - Dude.
然后我觉得他人很好
And I think he's really nice.
等你见到他开赛车吧  你真的会爱上他的
Wait till you see him race. Then you'll really fall in love.
兄弟
Dude!
干嘛  我只是
What? I was just...
所以  我什么时候能见你开赛车
So, when do I get to see you race?
丹尼才不会被这样迷倒
As if Denny would ever fall for that.
太棒了
Yes!
她几乎对赛车一无所知
She knew almost nothing about racing,
但不知为何  丹尼好像并不在乎
but for some reason, Denny didn't seem to mind.
我猜很快就能常在后视镜里看到她了
I assumed she would soon be in our rear-view mirror.
但到春天的时候  显然伊芙没有离开的意思
But by spring, it was clear Eve wasn't going anywhere.
我承认  我嫉妒他眼中只有她
I'll admit I envied the attention he lavished on her,
毕竟她有着对生拇指和丰满的臀部
with her Opposable thumbs and plump buttocks.
拇指对向性  指灵长类手的拇指能与其他四指对合的特点
在他日常的车里  对
In his regular car, yes.
他又懂什么教英语的事
Well, what does he know about teaching English?
对  我就这个意思
Yeah, my point exactly.
她对电视节目的品味
And her taste in television programs
实在是难以直视
left something to be desired.
你能别闹吗
Will you stop?
丹尼从不倦于取悦她
Denny never tired of pleasing her.
都是为了之后的奖励
All for his reward,
通常来说就是依偎着  互相轻抚
which usually meant lots of stroking and nuzzling.
-课上得怎么样  -挺好的
- How was your class? - It was good.
我嫉妒她迷人的微笑  她自如的大笑吗
Did I envy her engaging smile? Her effortless laugh?
也许吧
Perhaps, I did.
因为她是个人类  不像我
For she was a person, unlike me.
-我去做点早餐  -真的啊
- I'll go make us some breakfast. - Really?
-当然  -好的  谢了
- Yeah. - Okay, thanks.
你好啊  恩佐
Hey, Enzo.
你不介意我也爱他  对吗
You don't mind if I love him too, do you?
好像我有话语权一样
As if I had a say in the matter.
他们在海边的一栋华丽的豪宅
They were married at a magnificent palace
举行了婚礼
with its very own ocean.
那种地方我曾以为只存在于电视里
The kind of place I had assumed only existed on television.
我尽最大的努力帮忙了
I tried my best to be helpful.
我注意礼貌
I minded my manners,
忍住没有在精致的开胃菜盘上小餐一顿
resisted snacking on the trays of exquisite appetizers
并且永远只在
and made sure to do my business
离派对最远的花圃里解决内急
in the flowerbed farthest from the festivities.
这个地方属于伊芙的父母  崔西和麦克斯韦
The place belonged to Eve's parents, Trish and Maxwell...
我承认我一开始错把他们认成了双胞胎
who I confess I first mistook for twins.
-都弄好了吗  -都好了
- We're good？ Yeah? - Yeah.
下面有请护戒使者送上戒指
Would the bearer please bring the rings forward?
那一刻终于来临
When the time came,
我按所教的做了  看在丹尼的份上
I did as I was instructed, for Denny's sake.
-好孩子  -来吧恩佐  到这儿来伙计
- Good boy. - Come on, Enz. Come here, bud.
嘿  好孩子
Hey. Good boy.
此戒指为凭  你我结为夫妻
With this ring, I thee wed.
伊芙呢
Eve?
此戒指为凭  你我结为夫妻
With this ring, I thee wed.
就这样  我们成为了一家人
And so, we became a family...
当然各人对此的热忱总有高低
...to varying degrees of enthusiasm.
他怎么着也该为自己的婚礼刮刮胡子吧
Think he could've shaved for his own wedding?
-麦克斯韦  -干嘛
- Maxwell. - What?
-只是我的一点观察评论  -拜托
- It's just an observation. - Oh, please.
你眼里谁都配不上她
No one's good enough for her in your eyes.
我挺喜欢他  真的  但我爱我的女儿
I like him, I do, but I love my daughter,
那个男的开赛车谋生
and the man races cars for a living.
你不觉得我有理由感到一点担忧吗
You don't think I'm within my rights to be a little concerned?
不  只要伊芙不担心就行了
No, not if Eve isn't.
我知道人们在我面前
I've learned that people will say
无所顾忌什么都敢说
just about anything in front of me,
因为我只是一条蠢狗
as I am only a dumb dog.
我上周给安迪·纽伯格打了个电话
I put a call in to Andy Neuberger last week.
他说像丹尼这样在车队
He said a driver who's been on the circuit
待了这么久的车手
as long as Denny has,
假如他的事业能有破晓
it it was gonna break for him,
他到现在应该已经有所成就了
most likely would've happened by now.
但伊芙说他最近开得很不错
But Eve says he's been doing great lately.
我就知道你们在这儿  快点  吃蛋糕了
I knew I'd find you two in here. Come on, it's cake time.
你爸他在调他的酒呢
Daddy was making his drink.
婚礼之后  就搬了家
After the wedding came the move.
我对此有些纠结
I was of two minds about it.
我现在有地方闲逛了
I now had room to roam.
但旧公寓是属于我们两的  丹尼和我的
But the old apartment was ours, Denny and me.
我试着传达我的感受
I tried to communicate my feelings.
什么声音
What was that?
是恩佐弄的  他只是太兴奋了
It was Enzo. He's just excited.
但我的举动一如既往地被误解
But my gestures were inevitably misinterpreted.
此外  伊芙产生了一种神秘的新气场
Moreover, there was a mysterious new aura about Eve that,
不知为何  让我
for some reason, prevented me
没法保持对她的愤恨
from maintaining any resentment toward her.
是在沃特金斯峡谷  我在那儿总是开得很好
It's Watkins Glen, which I usually do really well at.
-是在纽约吗  -对  对
- And that's in New York, right? - Yeah. Yeah.
你可以请几天假
You could take a couple days off
我们可以早点过去
and we could get out there early.
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
等等  什么
Wait, what?
你吓到了
You freaked out?
什么  不  不  我没有  你不自在吗
Wha... No! No, I'm not! Wait, are you freaked out?
有一点吧  当然
A little, yeah.
是啊
Yeah.
你之前知道吗
Did you know about this?
我从来没有理解金钱的概念
I never really grasped the concept of money
以及人类为什么好像总是需要它
and why humans always seemed to be in need of it.
但丹尼越来越一门心思执着于此了
But Denny became more and more preoccupied with it.
太棒了
All right!
他开始比以往都刻苦地训练
He began to train harder than ever.
他承担了额外的教学工作
He took on extra teaching sessions,
尽可能地参加比赛
competed in every race he could.
我会想你的
I'll miss you.
也就意味着我与伊芙独处的时间越来越多
This meant my spending more and more time alone with Eve.
来吧恩佐  快回来
Come on, Enz. Come on.
老实讲  我还是没能
To be honest, I still didn't share
像丹尼那样毫不顾忌地喜欢她
Denny's overt affection for her.
好的伙计  太谢谢你了
Hey, buddy, thank you so much.
但我们协调出了自己的相处节奏
But we developed a rhythm of our own.
非常好
That's very nice.
时常  她甚至让我想起我自己的母亲
At times, she even reminded me of my own mother
她也会长叹一声  耸耸肩膀仰身躺下
when she would sigh and shrug herself into a prone position.
身体里装着另一个全新的生命
It must be amazing to have a body
一定是种十分神奇的感觉
that can carry an entire creature inside.
当然  不是说绦虫  我曾经遭过那罪了
I mean, other than a tapeworm, which I've had.
你想知道这是什么感觉吗
Do you want to know what it feels like?
好孩子
Good boy.
你感觉到了吗
Did you feel that?
你感觉到里边踢了一下吗
Did you feel that kick?
哦乖孩子  过来
Oh, sweet boy, come here.
没事的  来吧  没事的
It's okay. Come here. That's okay.
我无法想象伊芙的魔法袋里发生着什么
I couldn't imagine what was going on inside Eve's magic sack
那里面正组装着小宝宝
where the baby was being assembled.
我只希望它能长得像我
I just hoped it would look like me.
恩佐  慢点  你就这一个
Enzo, slow down, it's your only one.
-它很舒适  -我很喜欢
- It's cozy. - I love it.
这看上去可能跟上次的一模一样
It probably looks exactly like the last one
我懂你  但
I got you, but...
你喜欢吗  我从派克市场买的
Do you like it? I got it from Pike Place.
它是百分百手工制造
It's like 100 percent handmade.
-这很  -是你最喜欢的那种粉色
- It's, uh... - Your favorite shade of pink.
确实
It is.
你还好吗
You okay?
我没事  我只是想看看戴上什么样
Yeah, I'm fine. I just want to see what it looks like on.
我们再能讨论一下找接生婆的事吗
Hey, can we talk about this whole midwife thing again?
-亲爱的  我们不是已经讲好了  -我知道
- Honey, we've been over this. - Yeah, I know.
我只是说  你知道  我是在医院出生的
I'm just saying. I mean, you know, I was born in a hospital,
你也是在医院出生的
you were born in a hospital.
我知道  但我真的很想在这儿生下孩子
I know, but I really want to do it here.
我是说  谭雅在家生的双胞胎
I mean, Tanya birthed her twins at home.
她说她雇的那两个女工做得非常好
And she said that these two women she used were amazing.
行吧
Okay.
-喜欢吗  -你好呀妈妈  圣诞快
- Like it? Hey. - Hi, Mom. Merry Chri...
好
Okay.
那人是什么什么彭斯基车队的
Someone from something-something Penske?
圣诞节还打
On Christmas Day?
你好
Hello.
是的  你好
Yeah, hi.
这顶帽子是什么
What is this hat?
-他们说狗狗是色盲  -好吧
- They say dogs can't see color. - Oh, Okay.
很显然  丹尼也是
Apparently, neither could Denny.
是的  我会
Yeah, I'll, um,
静候佳音  好
I hear back from you again, okay.
再见
Bye.
-谁啊  -是朱德·墨菲
- What is it? - That was Judd Murphy
来自潘斯科车队
from Team Penske.
他是个车手  在24小时戴托纳比赛中
He's down a driver and he just offered me
给我提供了一个席位
a seat in the 24 Hours of Daytona.
那很好  是吗
That's good, right?
只是很好吗  我是说  这太棒了
Good? I mean, it's great!
这可是戴托纳啊
It's Daytona.
我是说  这是我梦寐以求的机会
I mean, this is the shot I've been wanting.
这将改变我的全部
This could change everything for me.
天啊  丹尼  太棒了
Oh, my God, Denny, that's great!
这是一月最后一个周末
It's the last weekend of January.
所以呢  截止日期不是到2月15日吗
So? The due date isn't till February 15th.
已经就在眼前了
That's cutting it awful close.
你想和我一起去吗
Hey, what if you came with me? Huh?
我们不必  我们不必坐飞机的
We don't... we don't have to fly.
丹尼  我不想开车去佛罗里达
Denny. I'm not driving to Florida.
但你必须这么做
But you have to do this.
没什么很争论的  这是你的机会
There is nothing to debate here. This is your shot.
如果你成绩优异  这些大门都将敞开
If you finish well, all these doors start to open.
你一点都不担心时间吗
Oh, you're not worried about timing, at all?
你什么时候见过我提前做事了
When have you known me to be early for anything?
我从没见过谁发出这种声音
I didn't know a human could make such sounds.
三冠皇
The triple crown of...
然而丹尼太想念它
Denny missed it all however, as he was driving
他在戴托纳连夜比赛
through the night at Daytona.
丹尼·斯威夫特在22号赛车
Denny Swift in the 22 car
考虑到车队在第10名
putting in a tremendous performance,
他表现优异
considering the team was in 10th place.
你干得很棒  伊芙
You're doing wonderfully, Eve.
快到这场耐力赛的第17小时了
Approaching hour 17 of this marathon race,
真是倾盆大雨
and the rain is really pouring.
我想和丹尼说话  你能打他电话吗
I want to talk to Denny. Can you call him?
再加把劲  好吗
Just keep pushing, okay?
斯威夫特回到22号赛车
With Swift back in the 22 car,
他紧跟着17号赛车的尾部
he's snapping at the heels of car 17.
再来一次
One more push.
难以置信  丹尼·斯威夫特
Unbelievable! Denny Swift has taken the lead
以高超的技艺获得了领先
in a magnificent show of skill.
你好  小宝贝
0h, hi, sweetgirl.
-你真是我的小棉袄  -好吧
- You're nice and warm. - All right,
-我们给你们独处的时间  -谢谢
- we'll give you two some time alone. - Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
狗狗快走吧
Oh! Shoo now, pup!
不  它  它能留下
No, he... he can stay.
是的
Yeah. Oh...
恩佐
Enzo.
这一幕  史无前例
The scent was... unprecedented.
过来  帅哥  过来
Come here, sweet boy. Come here.
我从未见过如此美妙之物
I had never encountered a creature quite so beautiful.
佐伊
Zoe...
这是恩佐
this is Enzo.
他也是你家人
He's your family, too.
他会永远保护你
And he'll always protect you.
-你好  一切还好吗  -她很好
- Hey, how is everything? - Hi! She's fine.
-她好吗  -是的  很好
- She's okay? - Yes, just fine.
你好  是的
Hey. Yeah.
她在等她爸爸
She's been waiting for her daddy.
我应该在这里
I should've been here.
亲爱的  她才一天大
Honey, she's a day old.
我知道  但还是
I know, but still...
你现在就在这里
You're here now.
这是我们见面的原因
This is why we met.
为了完成这一完美的小事
To make this perfect little thing.
我还是不懂
I still don't understand.
我们输了  没什么大不了的
We lost. It's no big deal.
我们领先了一圈  进入最后赛程
We were leading by a lap, going into the last stint.
还有  我告诉墨菲我觉得能完赛  但是
And... I told Murph I felt up to finishing, but...
赞助商强迫他和这个来自加州的神童
the sponsors were pressuring him to go with this wonder kid
一起比赛  最近他开了好几场发布会
from California who'd been doing a bunch of press lately.
比赛十分钟后  这孩子撞到墙上了
Ten minutes in, the kid hit the wall.
整个赛车都撞毁了
Totaled the car.
但你表现很好
But you drove well.
是的  如果车队没有完赛
Yeah, it doesn't really mean a whole lot
就没有什么意义
if your team doesn't finish.
没关系
It's okay.
真的  还会有其他比赛
Really. There's gonna be other races.
-是的  -是的
- Yeah. - Yeah.
佐伊  你还好吗
Oh, Zoe. You okay?
她在哪  已经  已经那么久了
Where is she? It's... it's been too long!
这对双胞胎  都没怎么来过
The twins, who rarely visited,
现在经常来  用耀眼的礼物
now stopped by frequently to clutter our home
把家里搞得一团糟
with garish gifts.
丹尼假装不介意
Denny pretended not to mind,
但是斑马让我感到不安
but something about the zebra put me ill at ease.
看着这些漂亮的眼睛
Look at those pretty eyes.
你好  小女孩
Hello, baby girl.
爸爸  她要换尿布了
Dad, she needs a change.
我来  好吗
Oh, I'll do it! Yeah?
是的  奶奶来
Yeah, Grandma's got you.
丹尼
Denny!
走吧
There you go.
-来了  -谢谢
- It's coming along. - Thanks.
顺便说  我看了你的几场比赛
I watched some of that race of yours, by the way.
那小伙子怎么样  撞车的那个
How's that boy doing, the one who crashed?
我们以前聊过这个
We had this conversation before.
你现在有女儿了
Still, you have a daughter now.
比如说  你受伤严重
Say, for instance. You get seriously injured,
-或上帝禁区  死了  -我不会
- or God forbid, killed... - I won't.
-这你没法保证  -不  我能
- You can't promise that. - Yes, I can.
我  我向你保证我会永远养育
I... I promise you that I will always provide
伊芙和佐伊  无论发生什么
for Eve and Zoe, no matter what.
我发誓我将把自身安全放在首位
And I swear to you that I will put my safety first,
即使意味着输掉我参加的每一场比赛
even if that means losing every race that I enter.
再见  亲爱的  爱你
Bye. Bye, honey. Love you.
这让我吃惊  像我们的小佐伊
It amazed me, the power exerted by a creature
-展现的力量  -你好
- as tiny as our little Zoé. - Hi.
也是她向我展示的力量
A power she wielded over me as well...
堪比地球在运行轨道中对月球的力量
with no more effort than the earth does the moon in its orbit.
我是她玩乐中不可或缺的一员
I was an integral figure in her entertainment,
跟着网球跳跃
leaping after tennis balls
跳跃回来抓住它
and scrambling back to catch them
然后像个四条腿的小丑跳动着再抓住它
then dancing like a four-legged clown to catch them again.
跑
Run!
准备好了吗  小寿星
You ready, birthday girl?
好  我们开始吧  我们开始吧
Okay, here we go, here we go.
我沉浸在她的世界中
I was so immersed in her world
我都记不清岁月了
that I'd lose count of the weeks and months.
准备  预备  跑
Ready, steady... go!
当她能告诉玩伴
And when she would tell her playmates
我是她的大哥哥时  我的心充满自豪
that I was her big brother, my heart would swell with pride.
热土豆
Hot potato!
臭抽屉
Ahh! Stinky Drawers!
她来了
Oh! She's coming in.
-去吧  -她热切地来了  恩佐
- Go! - She's coming in hot! Enzo!
好孩子
Good boy.
每个人都要排队领吃的
Everyone has to wait their turn for a snack,
斑马也是  是吗  老师
even zebras. Right, teacher?
-爸爸  -你好
- Daddy! - Hi! Hey.
抱歉我错过了你的诗朗诵
Hey, I'm sorry I missed your dance recital.
妈妈都跟我说了
Mommy told me all about it.
-你赢了吗  -不  小甜豆  不是这个
- Did you win? - No, sweet pea, not this one.
更好吗
Better?
比你想象的还好
You have no idea.
多谢你照料她们母女  恩佐
Thanks for taking care of our girls, Enz.
这是什么
Okay, so what do we got here?
这是我的二年级教室
Well, this is my second-grade class.
感觉我总是在赛道上或在飞机上
Feels like I'm always at the track or getting on a plane.
我有时也有这种感觉
Feels that way for me too sometimes.
你会适应的
It'll get easier.
你好吗
You okay?
有点头痛  我忙着改考卷很晚才睡
Just a headache. I was up late grading papers.
你知道  不该花那么久时间的
It wasn't supposed to take this long, you know.
梦想永远是一级方程式  但感觉
Dream's always been Formula One, but it feels
我就像在水上行走一样
like I'm just kind of treading water.
第一个弯道不可能决定比赛胜负
Hey, no race was ever won on the first corner.
是的
Yeah.
你依然热爱比赛  是吗
You still love it, don't you?
是的  当然  是的
Yeah, of course. Yeah.
也许这还不够
Maybe that's not enough.
我不知道
I don't know.
艾派克斯让我参加下周末拉古那·塞卡赛道比赛
Apex offered me a seat at Laguna Seca for next weekend.
我  我告诉他们我需要考虑一下
I... I told them I needed to think about it.
你累了
You're just tired.
是的
Yeah.
我彻夜未眠思考丹尼说的话
I spent a sleepless night contemplating what Denny had said.
退出比赛吗
Quit racing?
他是个赛车手  就像我是条狗
He was a racecar driver the way I was a dog.
这是他的本性
It was his nature.
他的命运
His destiny.
根据蒙古民间传说
According to Mongolian folklore,
狗狗能看透精神世界
the dogs are able to see into the spirit world...
佐伊  亲爱的  晚饭好了
Zoe, honey, dinner's ready!
我想等爸爸
I want to wait for Daddy.
爸爸今晚要上课
Daddy's teaching tonight.
再等五分钟好吗
Five more minutes? Ugh!
好吧  恩佐  吃完饭
Okay. Enzo, dinner!
来了
Yes!
我对丹尼的所有担忧都被气味掩盖了
And then all my worries about Denny were eclipsed by a smell.
从她耳朵和窦道的味道  像是
An odor coming from her ears and sinuses like...
腐烂的味道  像是朽木
decay. Like rotting wood.
这种轻率的语气  我应该警告她的
Given a facile tongue, I could have warned her.
也别让我为难  兄弟
Don't give me a hard time, too, buddy.
相反  我能做的就是观察感受内心空虚
Instead, all I could do was watch and feel empty inside
因为我爱莫能助
because there was nothing I could do to help her.
在斑马沉默的注视中
In the zebra's mute stare,
我能感到它嘲笑窘迫
I could sense it mocking my predicament.
伊芙让我保护201%
Eve had assigned me to protect 201%.
但没人来保护伊芙
But no one had been assigned to protect Eve.
轻点  轻点  你要吵醒佐伊了
Hey, hey, shh. You're gonna wake up Zoe.
来
Come on.
你什么时候开始看我比赛的
Since when do you watch my incars?
你过弯怎么会比其他赛车
How come you go through the turns
快这么多
so much faster than the other cars?
这个
Well...
很多车手害怕下雨
most drivers are afraid of the rain,
因为这是无法预测的天气变化
because it's an unpredictable element.
他们不得不做出应对
They're forced to react to it.
如果他们这时才加速
And if they're reacting at speed...
他们可能就太迟了  所以他们会害怕
then they're probably too late, so they should be afraid of it.
我看着都怕
Well, I'm afraid just watching it.
是的  但如果你有意操控赛车
Yeah, but if you intentionally make the car do something,
你不必预测  你  你能掌控结果
you don't have to predict. You... you control the outcome.
所以你在赛车打滑前先打滑赛车吗
So, you skid the car before it skids itself?
是的
Yeah.
是的  当我在赛车内
Yeah. When I'm in a race car,
命运掌握在自己手里
I'm the creator of my own destiny.
你所看到的都是你想看到的
"That which you manifest is before you."
你要自己创造条件  雨就是雨
Create your own conditions and rain is just rain.
明早打电话给
Tomorrow morning you're gonna call the folks
艾派克斯的人  告诉他们
at Apex and you're gonna tell them
在拉古那·塞卡赛道见面
that you'll see them in Laguna Seca.
别放弃  永远别放弃
And you can't give up, not ever.
不为了我们  也不为了任何人
Not for us. Not for anyone.
答应我
Promise me.
我答应你
I promise.
那一刻  我终于明白了丹尼对伊的爱
At that moment, I finally understood Denny's love for Eve
也明白了为什么这么长时间以来
and why, for so long,
我一直不敢去爱她
I had been afraid to love her myself.
她是我不可预见的因素
She was my unpredictable element.
她就是我的雨
She was my rain.
看来今天天气不错
It's looking to be a beautiful day here
加利福尼亚州拉古那·塞卡赛道的萨利纳斯赛车场
at Laguna Seca Raceway in Salinas, California.
迎来43辆GT赛车以及实力雄厚的赛车手
We have a deep field of 43 GT cars and an impressive roster
参与比赛
of drivers.
妈咪  收拾下你的东西
Mommy? Go pack your bag.
我们去要爷爷奶奶家住几天
We're gonna to Grandma and Grandpa's for a few days
直到爸爸回家  好吗
until Daddy gets home. Okay?
-你生病了吗  -我只是需要休息
- Are you feeling sick? - I just really need to rest.
可以吗
Please?
去吧  这一切发生得太快了
Come on. It all happened so fast.
五分钟里  她们就都离开了
In five minutes, they were gone.
但我没死  我还活着
But I wasn't gone. I was still there.
丹尼常说恐慌是赛车手最大的敌人
Denny always said panic's a driver's worst enemy.
我不恐慌  我没有过度矫正也没有感到过度惊吓
So, I did not panic. I did not over correct or freeze,
即使我知道丹尼至少
even though I knew Denny wouldn't be home
两天之后才能回家
for at least another two days.
但是我是一条狗
But I'm a dog.
当上帝设计不让狗使用拇指的时候
And when God denied dogs the use of thumbs,
上帝就给了我们长时间不进食
He gave us the ability to survive
也不饿死的能力
without food for extended periods.
虽然拇指很有帮助
So, although a thumb would've been very helpful,
比如用它来转门把手
allowing me to turn a doorknob, for instance,
我第二有用的能力是我不用吃也能活着
my second-best tool was my ability to go without food.
我与世隔绝的时间越长  我就越焦虑
The longer my isolation continued, the more anxious I became.
如果丹尼再也不回来了该怎么办
What if Denny never returned?
饮用水是有限的
With only a limited supply of drinking water,
我不知道我还能坚持多久
I had no way of knowing how long I'd have to make it last.
我靠那几只佐伊掉下去的奇怪芝士
I sustained myself with the odd stray Cheen'o
维持自己的生命
Zoe had dropped...
忍受了在垫子上方便的羞辱
and suffered the indignity of relieving myself on the mat...
一直等到我的苦难结束
waiting for my ordeal to end.
在独处了大约40个小时后
It was roughly 40 hours into my solitude
我开始出现幻觉
when I think I began to hallucinate.
我刚发现了一些酸奶洒在地上
I 'd just discovered some remnants of spilled yogurt
然后听见了响声
when I heard a noise.
那是斑马
It was the zebra.
当他野蛮的表演模仿剧的时候
as it performed its brutal burlesque...
我真的不知道自己还能忍多久
Not sure how much more I could abide.
我跑了出去  希望看到的这些只是幻觉
I ran out, hoping that what I had seen was only in my mind,
由于缺乏葡萄糖而产生的恶魔般的幻觉
a demonic vision driven by lack of glucose.
但不知怎么的  我知道这一切是真的
But somehow, I knew that it was true
真的发生了一些糟糕的事情
and that something terrible had happened.
有人在家吗
Anyone home?
恩佐  你怎么来了  快过来
Enz, hey. What are you doing? Come here.
恩佐  过来
Enzo, come here!
来吧  兄弟
Come here, bud. Hey.
发生什么了  伊在哪
What happened? Where is Eve?
伊
Eve?
伊和佐伊还在那吗
Are Eve and Zoe still there?
我能和她聊聊吗
Can I talk to her?
我在家  恩佐也在
Yeah. I'm at the house. Enzo is here.
等等  伊芙  他这段时间一直在这吗
Wait, Eve, wait, hold... He's been here the whole time?
我以为你把他带走了
I thought you took him with you!
不  我该走了  我得照顾他
No, I got to go. I got to take care of him.
你唯一用过的地方是这块垫子吗
The mat was the only place you used, huh?
来这  伙计  吃吧
Come here, bud. There you go.
-爸爸  我好想你  -我也想你
- Daddy, I missed you! - Oh! I missed you, too.
我可以给我的动物打个招呼吗
Can I say hi to my animals?
去吧  当然可以  甜心
Yeah, go up. Sure, sweetheart.
我试着理解
I'm just trying to understand.
我觉得很不舒服  我也不知道
Ugh. I felt so sick I wasn't thinking.
医生觉得可能是病毒感染
The doctor thinks it's maybe something viral.
嗨  老兄
Hi, buddy. Hi.
恩佐  我很抱歉
Enz, I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
佐伊  我的动物出事了
Zoe? Something happened to my animals!
这真是一团糟
This is a mess.
我不懂他为什么要这样做  佐伊  别哭了
I... I don't understand why he'd do this. Zoe, stop crying.
我要去找他
I'm gonna go find him.
你给我过来  过来
Get over here. Get over here!
坏狗狗  过来
Bad dog! Come on!
看看你都干了什么  好好看看
Look what you did. Look what you did!
看见了吗  你为什么要这样做
You see that? Why would you do that?
坏狗狗  蠢狗  丹尼  别这样
Bad dog! You stupid dog! Denny, stop!
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
我只有一个想法
I had only one thought,
那斑马肯定在我离开之后
The zebra must have reassembled itself
缝好了自己  然后攻击了剩下的动物
and attacked the remaining animals after I left.
我应该一有机会就把它杀了的
I should've destroyed the demon when I had the chance.
我不应该吃这个的  就算你把我杀了
I should've eaten it, even if it killed me.
抱歉  恩佐
I'm so sorry, Enz.
我保证我再也不会这样了
I promise I'll never do that again.
你这只坚强的老狗
You're a tough old dog.
来吧  过来吧
Come on. Come on.
顺便提一嘴  我赢了
I won, by the way.
像是班上的第一名
Like first in class?
全年级第一名
First overall.
另外  在艾派克斯永远保有一席之地
Plus, a permanent seat in the Apex prototype.
天啊  丹尼
Oh, my God, Denny!
天啊  他们让我马上加入
Oh, my God! They want me down in Sonoma
索诺玛的训练
to start training with the team right away.
真为你骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
我想我们可以一起去
I was thinking we could all go on the road?
是的  至少在夏天之前
Yes. Maybe at least for the summer?
一起参加所有的比赛  干所有事
Yeah, go to all the races and everything?
天啊
Oh, my God.
在比赛中  你的视线要一直跟着你的车
In racing, your car goes where your eyes go.
一个无法将目光从墙上移开的车手
A driver who cannot tear his gaze from the wall
会不可避免的撞上那堵墙
will inevitably meet that wall.
但当一个车手感觉他的轮胎
But the driver who looks down the track
不受他的控制时
as he feels his tires break free,
他依旧继续控制着赛车以及他的命运
that driver will maintain control of his car and his destiny.
我发现丹尼就是这样做的
I realized this was what Denny had done.
他胜利了
He had manifested a win
因为他知道我们需要胜利
because he knew we needed one.
等她放学之后我们再见
And then we'll just meet you after she's done with school
钥匙
Keys.
-好  晚上我给你打电话  -好的
- Okay. I'll call you tonight. - Okay.
再见  伙计  再见  孩子  我需要这个  拭目以待
Bye, bud. Hey, kiddo, I need that. Let's see.
谢谢你  谢谢你
Thank you. Thank you.
-过得开心  -拜拜
- Have fun. -Bye.
拜拜  爸爸
Bye, Daddy!
-你好  妈妈  -你好呀
- Hi, Mom. - Hi.
你怎么样了
I wanted to see how you're feeling.
我很好  好多了
I'm fine. Much better.
佐伊上学的时候我会带恩佐去散步
I'm taking Enzo for a hike while Zoe's at school.
我要减肥  太恶心了
I need to get into shape, I feel so gross.
宝贝  你脆弱得像只小灵狗
Honey, you're frail as a whippet.
-丹尼又出城了吗  -我不想谈这个
- Is Denny out of town again? - Mom, I'm not getting into this.
我听爸爸说得够多了
I hear enough about it from Dad.
宝贝  我只是随便说说
Sweetheart, I'm really just asking.
我知道
I know.
我要走了  我一会儿打给你  我爱你
Um, I got to go. I'll call you later. I love you.
-我爱你  -拜拜
- I love you. - Bye.
没事
It's okay.
我没事
I'm okay.
有时候  希望能说出话的欲望
There are moments when the urge to speak
真让人抓狂
is truly maddening.
这是一个数字
There's a number.
有时候我讨厌我只是一条狗
Sometimes I hate what I am.
过来吧
Hey, come on.
来这里
Come here.
她会好起来的
Yeah, she's gonna be okay.
-谢谢你  麦克  -不用客气  老兄
- Appreciate this, Mike. - No problem, man.
他们甚至不做活组织检查
They're talking about not even doing
直接手术把它取出来进去
a biopsy, just go in and get it,
不管是不是恶性的
you know, malignant or not.
你  你想我帮你打电话给艾派克斯吗
You, um, you want me to call Apex for you?
不  我准备好了
Nah, I already did.
告诉他们我这一赛季要离队  可能更久
Told them I'm out for the season, maybe longer.
我必须在这里
I have to be here.
好的  恩佐  今晚你和麦克叔叔睡
Okay, Enzo, you're gonna bunk with Uncle Mike tonight.
怎么样  你要照顾好麦克  好吗
What do you say about that? You be good for Mike, okay?
过几天见
See you in a couple days.
我会尽量陪伴着他
I would have done anything to stay with him.
但是作为一只狗  人们不允许我踏入医院
But being a dog, I was not allowed into the hospital
去听诊断结果或者是讨论如何选择
to hear the diagnosis or the options being discussed.
我当时差不多十岁
I was almost ten years old
没有人信任我
but no one confided in me,
也没有人期望我能做什么
or expected anything except that
除了希望我能控制自己的叫声
I control my barking
还希望我在外面忙自己的
and do my business outside.
斑马在某个地方跳
Somewhere the zebra was dancing.
我想过逃跑
I thought about escaping.
把大家都赶走
I wanted to push everyone away
和我的祖先一起生活在
and run off to live with my ancestors
蒙古的高沙漠平原上
on the high desert plains of Mongolia.
我相信丹尼有能力
I might have, too, if not for my absolute faith
让一切恢复正常
in Denny's ability to make things right again.
手术结束了
She's out of surgery.
我们只需要等着她醒来
Now we just wait and... see how she responds.
兄弟
Hi, pal.
这台车疲倦了
The trans machine get snaps
离合器坏了  刹车过快导致过热
The clutch fails. Brakes go soft from overheating.
差的车手会撞毁赛车  一般的会退出
The poor driver will crash. The average driver will quit.
而高超的司机能解决这个问题
But the great driver will drive through the problem.
嗨  听我说
Hey, listen.
我明天有课
I have to teach tomorrow,
所以你放学之后先去卡罗琳家
so you're gonna go to Caroline's house after school
我六点钟来接你
and I'll pick you up at six.
爸爸
Daddy?
妈妈什么时候回家
When's Mommy gonna come home?
我不知道  孩子
I don't know, pal.
很快  我希望
Soon, I hope.
伟大的车手找到了继续比赛的方法
The great driver finds a way to keep racing.
晚安  爸爸
Good night, Daddy.
-我爱你  -我也爱你
- Love you. - Love you, too.
有问题吗  你不是喜欢烤奶酪吗
Oh, what's the matter? You like grilled cheese.
但到午餐时间就冷了
But it's gonna be cold by lunchtime.
知道吗  得让爸爸休息一会儿
You know, give your dad a break.
我又要工作又要学习  孩子
I'm kinda learning on the job here, kiddo.
你老婆还在上班吗
Your wife works too, huh?
我妈妈在医院  她大脑生病了
My mommy's in the hospital. Her brain got sick.
好的  放学后我来接你
Okay, so I'm gonna pick you up right after school.
但今天是周四  可能会延长
But today's Tuesday. I have an extended day.
什么时候才能结束
Okay, so what time is that over?
问妈妈  她知道
Ask Mommy. She knows.
-再见 亲爱的  -再见
- Bye,sweetheart. - Bye.
你好  妈妈
Hi, Mommy.
日复一日
Days became weeks,
伊芙还没有从医院回家
and still Eve did not come home from the hospital.
你会没事的
You're gonna be okay.
一切都会好起来的
Everything's gonna be okay.
你现在应该坐下了
Maybe you should sit down now.
关心丹尼的朋友们给他特殊照顾
The people who cared about Denny made special accommodations.
麦克在汽车修理场给他找了个兼职
Mike got him some part-time work at the garage
并且随叫随到地照顾我
and looked after me whenever Denny asked.
还有他迫不得已学的
And there were other skills
其他的技能
he was forced to master.
-你弄疼我了  -好的
- You're hurting me! - Okay.
对不起
I'm sorry.
佐伊在绿湖夏冷营
Zoe spent the hot summer days-
度过了整个暑假
at a kids' camp over by Green Lake...
嗨  亲爱的
Hi, sweetheart.
偶尔跟双胞胎过夜
And the occasional night with the twins.
再见
Bye!
我们走吧
Here we go.
那些夜晚  丹尼在医院过夜
On those nights, Denny would stay late
陪着伊芙
at the hospital with Eve.
我们一回到家，他总是非常沉闷
When we'd come home, he would be very quiet.
然后要靠我带他出去遛遛
And then it would fall to me to provide what he needed.
到了秋天  我们有点像
By autumn, we'd come to resemble
经验丰富的后勤维修人员
something like a seasoned pit crew.
-安那贝尔  帕克  -是的  预感
- Annabelle, Parker... - Yeah. Anticipating,
调整  纠正
adjusting, correcting.
再见  等下  亲爱的  这里
Have a great day! Wait, sweetheart, here.
-你的午餐  -好的  谢谢  爸爸
- Here's your lunch. - Okay... Thanks, Daddy.
再见  拜拜  再见
See you later. Bye. Bye.
拜
Bye.
你说呢  恩佐
What do you say, Enz?
你会喜欢这个的  准备好了吗
You're gonna like this one. You ready?
Zoe
Hey, Zoe!
晚饭好啦
Dinner!
本杰明快要出跑道了
Benjamin is going around the outside,
紧接着是威尔森和尼尔
and it's Wilson and Neal.
不公平  是那辆红色车的错
No fair. It's the red car's fault!
是  也不完全是
Well,yes and no.
看  你应该负责自己在跑道上的位置
See, you've got to be in charge of your position on the track.
这是那辆红车刚刚在做的
That's what the red car was doing.
但有时候  在比赛中
At some point, in every race,
你要想赢就必须冒险
you got to take a risk if you want to win.
天啊  你妈妈会杀了我的
Oh, my God! Your mom is gonna kill me.
那天晚上   丹尼接到电话
That night, Denny got the call.
医生们最终同意让伊芙回家
The doctors were finally allowing Eve to come home,
只是她不会回我们的家
only she wouldn't be coming home to us.
为什么妈妈不能和我们在一起
Why can't Mommy stay with us?
快了 她快回来了
Well, she will soon.
但我们觉得你爷爷奶奶全天在家
But we thought since your grandparents are home all the time,
你妈妈跟他们住在一起是最好的选择
it'd be best if she just stayed with them.
只是暂时的
Just for now.
妈妈回来了
Mommy's here!
-佐伊  -没关系  妈妈
- Oh, Zoe... - That's fine, Mom.
我的孩子
Oh, my baby.
-我一直在等你  -我也是
- I've been waiting for this. - Me, too.
还是她  伙计
It's still her, boy.
雪花落在松鼠身上  落在海狸身上
"And it was snowing on a squirrel, it was snowing on a beaver"
落在每个人的身上
"and it was snowing on everyone."
但之后他说  看  跟我们想的一样
"But then he said, 'Oh, look, just as we thought.'"
然后Boggan说  许愿
And Bogdan said, 'Wish.'
查尔斯 把愿望写在一张纸条上
"Charles wrote his wish on a piece of paper..."
我不  我不明白  你刚说的什么意思
I don't... I don't understand. What exactly are you asking?
麦克斯和我觉得佐伊应该和我们住这
Max and I think Zoe should stay here with us.
至少等
At least until...
等什么  我们现在就认为
Until what? Are we just assuming now
她挺不过去了吗
that she's not gonna make it?
我们都祈祷最好的结果
We're all praying for the best,
但你听医生说了
but you heard what her doctor said.
这可能是佐伊和她妈妈仅有的时间了
This might be the only time Zoe has with her mother.
我可以送她上下学  或者你也行
I can drive her to and from school. Or you can.
随你定
Whatever you want.
也  也欢迎你一起过来住
And... and you're welcome to stay here, too.
我们只是不觉得你
We just didn't think that you...
由你来决定
It's really up to you.
我要跟伊芙商量
I'll talk about it with Eve.
过来
Come on.
他们只是想帮我们  丹尼
They just want to help us, Denny.
我知道
I know.
重要的是你想要什么
What matters is what you want.
我想回到以前的生活
I want my old life back.
我爸跟你相处的还好吗  他答应过我的
Has my dad been any better with you? He promised he would be.
他很好  我们很好  真的  你就
Yeah, he's fine. We're fine, really. You just...
你就照顾好自己  好吗
You just keep focused on you. Okay?
幸运如我
Knock wood.
再过几星期  我就能恢复些力气
In a few weeks I'll get some strength back
我们就可以一块回家了
and we can both come home again.
-好吗  -好的
- Right? - Right.
我想让你再去比赛
I want you to start racing again.
你离开赛场太久了
You've been away from it for too long.
以后再说
We'll see.
你不能因为我而停下
I can't be the reason that you quit.
你答应过我你不会放弃
You promised me that you wouldn't quit.
我不会
I won't.
休息会吧
Get some sleep...
好吗
okay?
我爱你
I love you.
我更爱你
I love you so much.
做个人肯定很难
It must be so difficult being a person.
有时我很怀疑自己是否能做到那样的沟通
Sometimes I doubt my ability to interact on such a level,
但我知道要想成为我想做的那种人
but I know it's required if I'm to become the human
那是必须的
I hope to be.
照顾好我们的姑娘们  恩佐
Take care of our girls, Enzo.
我整晚保持清醒  之后的许多夜晚也是
I stayed awake all that night and many others that followed.
恶魔就要奔向伊芙
The demon was coming for Eve.
但他必须先过我这关
But he would have to get through me first.
只有当别人醒来时我才敢放下守卫的职责
Only once the others awoke did I dare relinquish my guard duties.
懒狗
Lazy dog.
一些夜晚  丹尼和我一起守着
On some nights, Denny kept watch with me.
但他早晨不会休息
But he couldn't rest in the morning.
我接到了  接到了
I got it, I got it. Okay.
他必须在佐伊面前保持坚强
He had to stay strong for Zoe.
拉锯战  这下怎么样
Tug-o-war. What about this one?
我们已经进入拉锯战
Whoa! We've got a tug-o-war.
他会得到哪个呢  他会得到哪个
Which one's he gonna get? Which one's he gonna get?
开始了  我拿到了  结束了
Here it goes! I got it. It's over there!
恩佐  过来
Enz, come here.
好孩子
Good boy.
-记得吗  -记得
- Remember? - Yeah.
他无止境地忍耐着
His endurance knew no limits.
-一把网球拍  -是的
- Ah, hey... a tennis racket. - Yeah!
外公给你在我们俱乐部的网球课报名了
And Grandpa got you lessons at our club
在星期三的下午  难道不会很趣吗
on a Wednesday afternoons. Won't that be fun?
-肯定会  -我星期三不行
- Yeah! Actually. - Wednesday's not that good
我一整天都在修车厂
for me. I'm at the garage all day.
没关系  我们可以送你佐伊 对吗
That's all right. We can drive you, Zoe, right?
-没错  -没问题
-Yea h! - Yeah.
当伊芙的父母跟佐伊约定的时候
And when Eve's parents dated on Zoe,
他允许了
he let them.
他知道他们唯一的女儿身上发生的事
He understood this was their way
是他们移自己的注意力
of pushing out of their minds
的唯一方式
what was happening to their own daughter.
检查的结果是  当然  不可能
A task that was, of course, impossible.
-你们好  -给你个惊喜
- Hi. - Surprise!
什么惊喜
What's the surprise?
-先过来  -我们决定开个聚会
- Just come. - We decided to have a party.
我们要开聚会吗  我想
We're having a party? I think,
我想我穿得不太适合
I think I'm a little under-dressed.
你看起来帅呆了
You look incredibly handsome.
你确定你要这么做吗
Are you sure you're up for this?
我想要回家
I want to come home.
你想让你回家
I want you home.
特别想  你都想像不到
So bad, you have no idea.
你看到了吗
Do you see?
Do you?
我什么也不害怕
I'm not afraid of it anymore.
因为我知道这不是结局
Because I know it's not the end.
但你知道的  对吗
But you knew that, didn't you?
你清楚一切
You know everything.
不是所有的事情  不是
Not everything, no.
但我知道这是
But I know this...
伊芙灵魂最后的一次呼吸
Eve's last breath freed her soul.
我亲眼看到它消失
I saw it leave, myself.
离开到其它地方继续旅行
Released to continue its journey elsewhere.
这样很不错
That's nice.
那是小孩儿玩的  我现在必须要长大了
That's a baby game. I have to be a grown up now.
崔西刚给佐伊做了些吃的
Trish just fixed Zoe something to eat.
谢谢
Thank you.
所有那些人
All those people.
她的老朋友们
All her old friends.
-她的学生们  -是的  大家都爱她
- Students of hers. - Yeah, everyone loved her.
我一直觉得自己准备好了  你知道吗
I thought I'd be ready, you know?
我的意思是  我知道这天会来  但
I mean, I... I knew it was coming, but...
我没准备好
I wasn't ready.
一点都没
Not at all.
说实话  丹尼
Well, to be honest, Denny, that's...
那就是我们担心的
what's concerning us a little.
你没有做任何准备
That you haven't made any preparations.
你好像对自己的处境没有计划
You don't seem to have a plan in place.
计划  我不
Plan? I don't...
佐伊正在吃鸡蛋和吐烤面包
Zoe's eating an egg and some toast.
我们刚开始谈
We just started.
我以为
Oh, I thought...
对不起  开始谈什么
I'm sorry, started what?
你们谁能告诉我这到底是怎么回事
Can one of you tell me what exactly is going on here?
麦克斯韦和我正在商量
Um, Maxwell and I have been talking, and, um...
我们想是否可能
we were wondering if maybe
对我们大家都好
the best situation for all of us involved
让佐伊继续跟我们住在一起
might be if Zoe continued to live here with us.
-什么  -她现在需要一个稳定的环境
- What? - She needs stability right now.
老实说  我们不认为
And, frankly, we don't think
以你现在的处境能给她好的环境
you're in a position to provide that.
除非你不再回到赛场
Not if you're gonna return to racing.
你  你还要回到赛场吗
Are you... are you gonna go back to racing?
当然
Of course, yeah.
不是现在  但
Not right away, but...
等你去比赛  谁能照顾佐伊呢
And when you do, who's gonna take care of Zoe then?
我会照顾
I will.
-像你照顾伊芙那样吗  -麦克斯韦
- Like you did Eve? - Maxwell!
这到底是什么意思
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
丹尼  拜托  我们都没心情
Denny, please, none of us has the heart
现在跟你争论这个
to argue about this right now.
也许你要是能多陪她一点
Maybe if you'd been around more,
你就会发现情况不对
you'd have noticed something was wrong.
-可能就可以及早发现  -这么说不对
- Maybe it could've been caught in time. - That's not true!
因为伤心而已  丹尼  他只是太难过了
He's upset, Denny, he's just upset.
你觉得我没有无数次地
You don't think that I asked the doctors
问过医生这个问题吗
that question a thousand times?
我们都明白这一切我们无能为力
We all know there's nothing anybody could've done.
那跟这一切都没关系
That's not what this is about.
佐伊跟我回家  没有商量的余地
Zoe is coming home with me. End ofdiscussion!
我们只是想为了Zoe好
We just want to consider what's best for Zoe.
Zoe跟她父亲在一起才是为了她好
What's best for Zoe is that she is with her father
如果你们还想以后再见到她
And if you want to have any relationship with her,
我建议你们立刻停止这个事情
I suggest you stop pushing this issue right now!
看 我怎么跟你说的
See, what'd I tell you?
但是你还是可以见到她啊
But you could still be in her life,
想多久就多久
just as much as you want to.
我们有足够的时间和金钱
We have the time and the money to care
按照Eve希望的那样去照顾她
for her the way Eve would have wanted.
你可以继续你的全职赛车
You can continue to pursue your racing full-time.
够了够了 我不想再听了
I... I'm... I'm done. I'm done listening to this.
你没有给我们其他的选择
You're giving us no other choice.
Maxwell 你答应过我你不会这样
Maxwell, you promised me you wouldn't!
什么
Wha...
你在跟我开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
我刚给我妻子办完葬礼
I just buried my wife
现在你要因为我女儿的监护权起诉我
and you're suing me for custody of my daughter?
Denny 我 实在对不起
Denny, I'm... I'm so sorry.
我们完全不想这样的
This is not at all what we thought...
我吃完蛋啦
Finished my egg.
宝贝儿 进去收拾你的东西
Sweetheart, go inside and pack your things.
我们马上回家
We're gonna go home right now.
一切正常 甜心 你爸爸有些事情要去做
Everything's fine, honey.Your dad has some things to take care of,
所以你现在跟我们住一起
so you'll stay with us for now.
Zoe 去收拾东西 我们要走了
Zoe, go and get your stuff. We're leaving.
你觉得你是什么东西
Who the hell do you think you are?
你自己一个人应付不来的 你知道的
You can't do this alone and you know it.
当你又回去搞你那些比赛 连续消失
What happens when you're back to disappearing
好几天的时候 发生了什么
for days on end at those races of yours?
每个周末你都在飞机上
You're on a plane every weekend.
天啦 她出生的时候你都不在
You missed her birth, for Christ's sake!
你不能带走她
You're not taking her.
噢 我的老天
Oh, my God.
-你还  -我很好
- Are you... - I'm fine.
我说了我很好
I said I'm fine!
Denny 暂时就让她留下来吧
Denny, please let her stay. Just for now.
律师会提出一个折中方案的
The lawyers could come up with a compromise!
Zoe
Zoe!
我们回头再来拿你的玩具 好吗
We'll come back later for your dolls, okay?
好
Okay.
上车 宝贝儿
Get in the car, sweetheart.
你正在犯一个大错误
You're making a big mistake!
Enzo 上车
Enzo, get in.
现在不行 Enzo
Not now, Enzo.
什么 好吧
What? Okay.
我不知道电视上在演什么
I didn't know what was on.
我只知道他需要转移一下注意力
I only knew he needed a distraction.
过去Eve常常这样做
It was something Eve used to do
当Denny心情不好的时候
when Denny was down.
好呀 你这条狗
Okay, you crazy dog.
这是在1989年的卢森堡大奖赛上
It turned out to be the 1989 Luxembourg Grand Prix
爱尔兰车赛车手Kevin Finnerty York
in which the Irish driver Kevin Finnerty York
只用二档完成了最后20圈的比赛
finished victorious while driving the final 20 laps
赢得了冠军
with only two gears.
真正的冠军可以做到
A true champion can accomplish things
常人认为不可能的事情
a normal person would consider impossible.
Denny只需要记住这个
Denny just needed to remember that.
Mark谢谢你在家休息还接我的电话
Thanks for taking my call at home, Mark.
我只认识你这一个律师
You're the only lawyer that I know.
你也是我唯一相信的汽修工
And you're the only mechanic I trust.
放轻松 Denny 据你所说
Relax, Denny. From what you told me on the phone,
这案子很简单
this is open-and-shut.
-你女儿现在在哪里  -她想去上学
- Where is your daughter now? - She wanted to go to school.
我应该把她留在家里吗
Should I have kept her at home?
不用 让她去吧 你这是满足她的需求
No, that's good. You're responding to her needs.
他们想起诉你是个不称职的父亲
They're trying to claim you're an unfit parent
因为你职业有潜在的危险
because of the intrinsic dangers of your occupation.
这完全是假的
It's a totally bogus suit.
真不知道他们为什么要费心去归档
Can't imagine why they even bothered to file it.
我会要求简易判决 仅此而已
I'll demand a summary judgment and that'll be that.
我想 你 你是说不会可能存在
I mean, you're... you're saying there's not even a chance.
这里是华盛顿州
This is Washington State.
孩子总是会被判给亲生父母的
The child is always awarded to the biological parent.
不用担心
No question.
下午好 警官们
Afternoon, Officers.
你是Denny Swift吗
You Dennis Swift?
我去看看他是不是还在后面
I'll just check if he's still in the back.
我就是Denny Swift
I'm Denny Swift.
先生 请从柜台后面走出来好吗
Would you step out from behind the counter, sir?
好
Okay.
我们有张你的逮捕令
We have a warrant for your arrest.
这是个什么玩笑吗
Some kind of joke?
先生 请把手放在柜台上 把腿伸开
Sir, please place your hands on the counter and spread your legs.
好
Okay.
嘿 嘿 伙计 没事 不要紧
Hey, hey, buddy, it's okay, it's okay.
你可以告诉我需要多久吗
Can you tell me how long this is gonna take?
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent...
我要去接我女儿放学
I need to pick my daughter up from school.
Denny我可以帮你去接她
Denny, I can pick her up for you.
不 给Mark Finn打电话 他知道怎么做
No, call Mark Finn. He'll... he'll know what to do.
你知道哪边是右吗
Do you understand your right?
-我知道  -请这边走
- Yeah, I understand. -This way, please.
-给Mark Finn打电话 -待着
- Call Mark Finn. - Stay.
你们为什么要逮捕他
What are you arresting him for?
我以前只感到过一次这样的无助
I'd only felt such helplessness once before.
就是Eve倒在树林里的那天
The day Eve collapsed in the woods.
明天早上 咖啡 准时8:30
Coffee tomorrow morning, 8:30 sharp.
-我们过一遍所有细节 好吗  -好的
- We'll go over everything then, all right? - All right.
我们试过去接Zoe 但是
We tried picking Zoe up from school, but...
嗯 我知道 她外公外婆先一步接走她了
Yeah, I know, her grandparents got to her first.
他们故意算好了时间来的 兄弟 走
They timed this thing on purpose, man. Come on.
Mike 多谢
Thanks, Mike.
四级殴打罪是一个恶心的轻罪
Fourth-degree assault is a gross misdemeanor,
所以你不会有真的牢狱之灾
so it's unlikely you'll see any real jail time.
但是我们都知道这不是关键
But we both know that's not what this is about.
关键是如果你被定罪
There's almost no chance you'll be awarded custody
你几乎没有可能获得监护权了
if you're convicted.
现在 由于刑事指控
Now, because of the criminal charges,
法官批准了一项临时限制令
the judge granted a temporary restraining order.
这意味着你在90天之后才能再见到Zoe
That means you're looking at 90 days before you can see Zoe again.
不
No.
-不 我 我不能看  -你不得不这样
- No, I... I can't not see... - You're gonna have to.
Eve的父母已经提议终止你的监护权
Eve's parents already filed a motion to terminate your rights.
Mark 这简直疯了 是他抓住了我
Mark, this is crazy. He grabbed me.
有人证吗
Any witnesses?
Trish 我想 但是她当时背对着我们
Trish, I guess, but her back was to us.
我可以跟她谈谈
I can talk to her.
不 不要跟他们任何一个人谈 我认真的
No, do not speak to either of them, I mean it.
你会危及到整个案子的
You'll jeopardize your entire case.
现在为了给Zoe解释你为什么不在
Now, to explain your absence to Zoe
我们一致同意编个故事
we have agreed to invent a story
你正在欧洲帮一个队比赛
about you driving for a team in Europe.
我还设法争取到了信件交换
I also managed to negotiate a letter exchange.
90天啊
Ninety days!
这种不公让人难以忍受
The injustice was unbearable.
Denny先是失去了Eve
First, Denny lost Eve
现在又即将失去Zoe
and now he would be deprived of Zoe, too.
几个星期过去了 Denny苦苦挣扎
Denny struggled as the weeks passed.
虽然我很想成为一个人
While I very much wish to be human,
但作为一只狗 有一个好处是我会想念的
there is one advantage to being a dog that I will miss.
你觉得怎么样 Enzo
What do you think, Enzo?
那就是
It is this...
狗可以停止思考 降低新陈代谢
A dog can power down his psyche and slow his metabolism.
可以毫不费力地坐连续几个小时
He can sit for hours on end with no effort.
狗可以改变整个世界的节奏
A dog can change the tempo of the world,
人们只能听其摆布
but people are at its mercy.
喂
Hello?
你家狗最近怎么样了
What's the deal with the dog?
-怎么了  -你家狗
- Huh? - The dog.
Zoe一直问她的外公外婆 想见你家狗
Zoe's been asking her grandparents to see the dog.
当然 她可以见Enzo
Of course, she can see Enzo.
告诉她 狗狗一直待在Mike家
Tell her he's been staying at Mike's
我会让Mike周末带Enzo过去
and I can have Mike drop Enzo off this weekend.
-好的 我会传达  -好
- Okay. I'll fioat it. - Okay.
谢了 Mark
Thanks, Mark.
我的秘书说我们给你寄了一张发票
Listen, my secretary says we sent you an invoice.
-是 我已经付款了  -那是之前的费用
- Yeah, I paid that. - That was your prior invoice.
我知道你不能离开州 所以你不能再赛车
I realize you can't leave the state, so racing is not an option.
我有一些人在做律师助理 后勤人员
But I have people walking on this, paralegals, support staff.
嗯 我知道 Mark 我会
Yeah, I know, Mark. I'll...
找到钱付给你的
find a way to pay you.
很难理解我们的生活发生了这样的转变
It was hard to comprehend this turn our lives had taken.
Enzo 来这儿 Enzo
Enzo! Come here, Enzo!
在它进门之前
Make sure you wipe his paws off
一定要把它的爪子擦干净
before he comes in.
-外婆刚洗了地毯  -好的
- Grandma just had the carpets cleaned. - Okay.
我想爸爸了 你呢
I miss Daddy. Don't you?
我有生以来第一次庆幸自己不会说话
For the first time in my life, I was glad I couldn't talk.
我不知道该跟她说什么
I wouldn't know what to tell her.
Zoe睡觉之后
After Zoe went to sleep,
我找到了机会去监视这两位
I took the opportunity to spy on the twins.
那个人把我按到了地上
The man put me on the ground.
我断了一根肋骨 我的老天爷啊
I cracked a rib, for God's sake.
你看到发生了什么
You saw what happened!
律师说整个案子取决于
The lawyer said the whole case hinges
你能否证实我的陈述
on you corroborating my statement.
你必须要去作证
You need to testify.
一种黑暗在我心中酝酿
Inside me a darkness was brewing.
你就想想我们是为了谁 好吗
Just remember who we're doing this for, okay?
为了我们的外孙女啊 这才是最重要的
Our granddaughter. That's all that matters.
我并不是不屑于利用我作为一只狗
And I was not above using the tools of my dogness
来伸张正义
to exact justice.
怎么
What?
-你喜欢辣椒  -Maxwell
You like pepper? Maxwell.
我知道辣椒对我不好 但我还是吃了
I knew that pepper was bad for me, but I ate it anyway.
还不错 哈
Good, huh?
毕竟 我不过是一条愚蠢的狗
After all, I'm just a stupid dog.
这是我们所见过的第二长的牛市
It's the second longest bull market we've ever seen.
潜在的卖家尚未出手
Potential sellers have not bailed out.
我观察 我等着
I watched and I waited...
我的胃里 有一种浸泡过的难闻的混合物
as in my stomach, a foul concoction steeped.
来 快来 我们出去 快来
Come on. Come on, we got to go outside, come on.
快来 我们走 动起来 快点
Come on. Let's go, let's get busy, come on!
快来 走啊 动起来
Come on, let's go, let's get busy.
噢 不 不 不 不 不 不 不
Oh, no, no. No! No, no, no, no!
Trish 快下来
Trish! Get down here!
狗刚在地毯上大便了
The dog just took a liquid dump on the carpet!
铲斗在哪 噢 天
Where's the bucket? Oh, God.
Trish 你可以下来这里吗
Trish! Can you get down here?
有的你忙了 先生
You get busy, mister.
你的眼睛已经向前看了
Your eyes are already forward,
看着下一个转弯
looking at that next turn.
-等我一会儿啊  嘿 -好
- You know, give me a second, okay? Hey. - Sure.
怎么了 我还以为他们会留它到今天晚上
What happened? I thought they were keeping him until tonight.
对啊 据我所了解
Yeah. From what I understand,
Enzo并不是个理想的客人
Enzo wasn't exactly the ideal house-guest.
好吧 这边马上就结束了
Okay. Well, we're almost finished up here.
我已经有好几年没有看到过现场直播了
It'd been years since these old eyes had seen a live track.
我没有意识到自己错过了多少
I didn't realize just how much I'd missed it.
我甚至有一股强烈的感觉
I even felt the tug of my old dream
我曾梦想在他身边驾驶一辆真正的赛车
of driving in a real race car alongside him.
好了 我们来检查场地
All right, let's checker the session,
清理赛道 所有学生去大看台上
clear the track! All the students to the grandstand.
现在还不能回家 嘿 Denny 有时间吗
Nobody head home yet. Hey, Denny, got a minute?
等我一会儿
Give me a second.
卢卡
Luca!
唐  你好吗
Don, how are you?
很高兴见到你
Good to see you.
你好
Hello.
这是法拉利的卢卡 潘托尼
This is Luca Pantoni from Ferrari.
他从意大利过来看看我们
He's visiting us from Italy.
丹尼  斯威夫特
Denny Swift.
幸会
Pleasure.
这是新型号吗
Is this the new model?
是  刚出厂的
Yeah, direct from the factory.
当面更好看
It's even better-looking in person.
你知道吗  我看过你比赛  在代托纳
You know, I saw you race once. In Daytona.
那次比赛挺难的
Yeah, that was a tough one.
卢卡希望你带他看看赛道
Luca was hoping you could show him the track.
行啊
Yes, sir.
那是谁
Who is that?
意大利法拉利挖掘车手部门的主管
Head of driver development from Ferrari in Italy.
我估计他得开上一圈来熟悉车子
I figure it'll take him a lap to get comfortable
但下一圈  就要飞起来了
but next time by, it'll be a flyer.
来  跟着我
Come on, follow me.
来  恩佐
Come on, Enz.
上这来  伙计们  带它过来
Up here, guys. Bring it in.
现在看着  给你们上堂大师课
Now watch. You're getting a master class here.
你们有人开过那样的车吗
That said, any of you ever drive like that,
你们开这么快我会给黑旗的  会头晕
I will black flag you so fast your head will spin.
丹尼是专家
Denny's a professional.
怎么样
How was it?
真了不起
That was incredible. Ha!
应该的
You deserve it.
好了  表演结束
All right, show's over!
你觉得怎么样  小子
What'd you think, huh, boy?
明天见
See everybody tomorrow!
你是开过法拉利的人了  她漂亮不
You're a Ferrari guy. Isn't she a beaut?
我想给你份工作
I would like to offer you a job.
我在马拉内罗工作  工厂总部
I work in Maranello, the factory headquarters,
我们那有个很棒的赛道
and we have a wonderful track there.
你可以测试车
You'd be testing the cars.
谢谢你  潘托尼先生
Thank you, Mr. Pantoni,
但有些事情
but... there are certain things
阻止我离开这个国家
that keep me from leaving the country right now.
唐给我解释过你的问题
Don explained to me all about your troubles.
但如果你的情况有了变化
But if your situation should change,
随时可以联系我
my phone is on the card.
这是我的荣幸
It was a pleasure.
谢谢你
Thank you, sir.
过来
Come on.
他这些年一直念叨你
He's asked about you over the years.
我告诉他你和伊芙的事情
When I told him what you went through with Eve,
他就说可以雇你
he said he wanted to hire you. Huh.
我只知道  他很敬佩你为女儿做的争取
All I know is, he respects how you're fighting for your daughter.
但如果我没赢呢
And what if I don't win?
输个比赛也没什么丢脸的
There's no dishonor in losing the race,
不敢比赛才丢脸
there's only dishonor in not racing
因为害怕输
because you're afraid to lose.
去找你的学生吧  回赛道去
Now go find your students, get back on the track.
那才是你该待的地方
That's where you belong.
过来
Come on.
九十天似乎很久  哪怕是对我来说
Ninety days seemed an eternity, even for me.
但最终  第九十天还是到了
But at long last, day 90 arrived.
爸爸
Daddy!
恩佐
Enzo!
-我六点钟回来接她  -好
- I'll be back for her by six. - Okay.
-小心点  -谢谢
- Take care. - Thanks.
-想你  -想你
- Mrn. Missed you. - Missed you.
来吧
Come on.
来吧  恩佐  今天晚餐有惊喜
Come on, Enzo. I made something special for dinner.
爸爸
Daddy?
你是不是又要去欧洲了
Are you gonna go back to Europe soon?
还没有  宝贝
No, not yet, sweetheart.
但是  佐伊  你需要和外祖父母
But, Zoe, you need to stay with your grandparents
再多待一段时间  好吗
for just a little while longer, okay?
不  我想回家
No, I want to come home.
我知道你想
I know you do.
我也想你回来  比什么都想
And I want you to, more than anything,
但律师们还得决定
but... the lawyers still need to make a decision
你在哪里过会更好
about where it's best for you to live.
好吗  这就是妈妈死后会发生的事情
Okay? That's just part of what happens when someone's mommy dies.
就告诉他们  告诉他们我想回去
Just tell them. Tell them I want to live
和你  和恩佐一起过
back home with you and Enzo.
好
Okay.
我会告诉他们
I'll tell them.
去吧
There you go.
-拜  爸爸  -拜  宝贝
- Bye, Daddy. - Bye, baby.
每两周你能见她一次  直到判决出结果
You'll get her every other weekend until the trial.
那之后
After that...
孤注一掷
It's all or nothing.
听着  丹尼
Look, Denny, I...
我知道这不是你现在想听的
I know this isn't what you want to hear right now,
但他们的律师告诉我
but their attorney made it clear to me.
只要你放弃监护权
The suit, the criminal charges, it can all go away tomorrow,
诉讼  指控  明天都可以烟消云散
if you dropped your custody claim to 206.
我有责任来确保你明白
Now, I have an obligation to make sure you understand,
我们现在有优势了
we have leverage now.
我是说探视  特权
I'm talking visitation, privileges.
如果你被认为有袭击罪
Things we're gonna have a much harder time securing,
这些权利我们得花更大功夫来寻求
if you're found guilty of assault
并且佐伊的外祖父母会获得抚养权
and Zoe's grandparents are awarded custody.
优势
Leverage.
我不是说我们不能赢
I'm not saying we can't win.
我们可能赢
We might.
但也可能输  很大几率
But we could also lose. Big.
不能输  马克
Can't lose, Mark.
丹尼  没人不能输
Denny, anyone can lose.
你该知道这点
You, of all people, should know that.
你看  就考虑一下
Look, just... just give it some thought.
我知道丹尼在想什么
I knew what Denny was thinking.
只要他握住方向盘
If he just had a steering wheel to hold onto,
他的手就不会发抖
his hands wouldn't shake.
就你和我  恩佐
"Just you and me, Enzo."
夜跑的时候他总说这句
That's what he'd always say when we'd take our night runs.
跟上  恩佐  我们走吧
Come on, Enz! Let's go.
但不是这一晚
But not that night.
我们是在一起  但还是一个人
We were together, but alone.
我在设想一个计划
I began to devise a plan.
我们要在某天开车去佐伊的学校
We'd drive to Zoe's school one day,
偷偷地接上她  然后直接开去蒙特利尔
pick her up unannounced and then head straight for Montreal,
那里每年夏天会举办一个国际汽车赛
where they host a Grand Prix every summer.
恩佐  恩佐  待在那  恩佐  不
Enz? Enzo, stay where you are! Enzo, no!
天啊
Oh, God!
我没看见他
I... I didn't see him!
不关你的事
It's not your fault.
是我的错  蠢
It was mine. Stupid.
他怎么样
Is he okay?
还在呼吸
He's still breathing. Um...
我真是蠢
I'm so stupid.
把他带上你的车
Let's get him in your car.
车随眼动  我怎么会忘呢
Your car goes where your eyes go. How could I forget?
埃尔顿 森纳没必要死在伊莫拉的
Ayrton Senna did not have to die at Imola.
我去医院的路上一直这么想
That's what I was thinking on the way to the hospital.
他以每小时90英里的速度撞上了水泥围墙
He struck the concrete barrier
在塔姆布雷罗角
at the Tamburello coner at 190 miles an hour.
但据说  如果不是一小块悬架
But, by all accounts, he would've survived
他就可以活下来
if not for a small piece of suspension
那东西戳穿了他的头盔
that managed to penetrate his helmet.
直接到后面去
Straight to the back.
但我知道真相
But I know the truth.
森纳死的那天  他的身体已经完成任务
Senna died that day because his body had served its purpose.
他的灵魂学到了该学习的东西
His soul had learned what it came here to learn.
我也知道如果我认识到注定要
And I knew that if I had already learned what I was meant to...
我也会走的
I too would be gone.
但很明显  我还有事情要做
But apparently, I still had work to do.
大量的体内出血
Fair amount of internal bleeding.
还有部分肾受损
Also, some renal damage.
他非常幸运  不然会更糟的
He is very lucky. It could have been far worse.
老实说  斯威夫特先生 像这样的老狗
I have to be honest with you, Mr. Swift. An old dog like yours,
受这种程度的伤基本是不行了
this kind of injury's often the beginning of the end.
X射线  镇静剂  止痛药  夜间急症费
X-rays, sedative, pain meds and nighttime emergency fee
总共812美元
comes to 812 dollars.
谢谢
Thank you.
不好意思  你的卡不能用
I'm sorry, your card was declined.
这是我的借记卡
Oh. Okay, um, here's my debit.
说是存款不足  有什么问题吗
Uh, it says insufficient funds. Is there a problem?
我今天刚存了工资
Uh, I deposited my paycheck today,
可能只是要清算一下
so it probably just needs to clear.
我有些现金  300 美元
I do have some cash. I have... I have 300 dollars.
我明天一早就去银行
I can go to the bank first thing in the morning
然后把剩下的钱带来
and... and bring the rest by then.
没事  在所难免  写个300美元的收据
It's fine. These things happen. Write a receipt for the 300,
给苏珊留个条子让她明早开发票
leave a note for Susan to invoice the balance in the morning.
事实上
Actually, do you...
我可不可以留20美元
Are you okay if I keepjust 20 of it?
谢谢
Thank you.
你准备回家吗  伙计
You ready to go home? Huh, pal?
那些药让我几周里不断地做梦
The medication kept me in a near-constant dream state for weeks
它们让我如释重负
which I confess came as a relief.
可以替换丹尼脸上的表情
Anything to replace that look I'd seen on Denny's face.
这是否是个好决定  不由我说
It's not for me to say whether it's the right decision or not.
但是  无论如何
But, for what it's worth,
我百分之百地支持你
I support you on this a hundred percent.
我也是
Me, too.
你该这么做
You're doing what you have to do.
佐伊长大的时候会明白的
Zoe will understand when she's older.
探视时间和我们讨论的一样
The visitation schedule will be as we discussed.
加上  夏天三周时间
Plus, three weeks in the summer,
圣诞节和四月假期各一周
a week at Christmas, and the April school break.
但那些指控怎么办
But what about the charges?
它们会立即被撤销
They'll be dropped immediately.
像我说的  丹尼  我们有优势
Like I said, Denny, we had leverage.
我喉咙里猛然生起一阵惊恐
A sharp panic rose in my throat.
我需要支笔
I need a pen.
我还在做梦吗
Was I still dreaming?
这家伙是谁  这个冒名顶替的
Who was this person, this impostor?
他把丹尼怎么了
What had he done with Denny?
不好意思  只能找到这支
Sorry. Only one I could find.
然后一切都清楚了  那不是丹尼
And then all was revealed. Mmm, it wasn't Denny.
是那只斑马
It was the zebra.
我已经阻止过这个恶魔
I'd been in a position to prevent the demon
毁掉佐伊的玩具  并且失败了
from destroying Zoe's toys and I'd failed.
我知道得阻止它  但怎么做
I knew I had to stop it, but how?
恩佐  恩佐  把文件给我
Enzo! Enzo! Give me those papers!
过来  恩佐
Come here! Enzo!
它要去哪  出了窗户
Where'd he go? Out the window!
恩佐  把文件给我
Enzo, you give me those papers!
这不好笑  托尼  恩佐  放下来  别
It's not funny, Tony. Enzo, drop it! No!
这有点好笑
I mean, it's kind of funny.
好  我懂你的意思了  我明白了
Hey, hey, okay, you made your point. You made your point.
给他们的律师打电话
Call their lawyers.
说法庭见
Tell 'em we'll see 'em in court.
这一次我站恩佐
I'm with Enzo on this one.
你确定吗
You're sure?
我给伊芙承诺过
I made Eve a promise.
我不会放弃的
I'm not quitting.
伙计  我也要养条狗
Man, I got to get me a dog.
丹尼准备冒险了
Denny was prepared to risk everything.
输了案子就输了佐伊
Lose the case and he would lose Zoe.
像往常一样我注意到了他那早的呼吸
His breathing that moming struck me as unusual.
深吸入  快呼出
Deep inhalations, quick exhalations.
我认出了这个声音
It was a sound I recognized.
这是他在比赛前才用的呼吸
It was the way he breathed just before a race.
时候到了  恩佐
This is it, Enz.
是托尼
It's Tony.
伙计  谢谢你能过来
Hey, man. Thanks for coming by.
我本来要带它去宠物店
I would've brought him by the shop,
但它最近的表现不是很好
but he hasn't been doing too good lately.
可怜的小子
Yeah, poor little guy.
恩佐  看谁来了  是托尼
Hey Enz, look who's here. It's Tony!
恩佐老兄  你怎么样
Hey Enz, buddy. How you doing?
-祝你好运  丹  -谢了  兄弟
- Good luck, Den. - Thanks, man.
你想看电视吗
You want to watch TV?
狗不允许带上法庭
Dogs are not allowed in court,
所以我只能想象城镇另一边正在发生的事
so I was forced to imagine what was happening across town.
根据丹尼每晚对于事件的复述
I invented whole scenes in my head
我在脑海里构建了一整个场景
fueled by Denny's nightly retelling of the day's events
当然也得益于我不可否认的戏精本质
as well as my own admittedly melodramatic sensibility.
-反对  法官大人  -或许是我老了
- Objection, Your Honor! - Perhaps, it was my advanced age
但我发现自己的想象力越来越不靠谱
but I found my imagination increasingly prone to wandering.
不是的  先生  我当然没有
No, sir, I most definitely did not.
直到
Until...
有没有可能在某一时刻
Isn't it possible at some point
你决定要加速
you decided to speed up?
法官大人  反对  我已经回答过了
Your Honor, I object. Asked and answered.
你都不记得谋杀了
You don't even remember killing...
我马上到
I'm on my way.
发生了些事  伙计  你想一起去吗
Something's happened, bud. You want to come?
怎么了  丹
What's going on, Den?
费了点脑筋  我搞清了事情发生的原委
With some effort, I was able to decipher what had happened.
愿上帝保佑
So help me God.
今天是崔西作证的日子
Today was the day Trish had testified.
你能否向法庭解释这项人身侵犯指控
Can you please tell the court about the alleged assault?
确实是像我丈夫说的那样
It happened the way my husband said it did.
所以  你亲眼目睹了丹尼·斯威夫特
So, you personally witnessed Denny Swift
把你的丈夫  年长他20岁的老人推倒
throw your husband, a man 20 years his senior, to the ground
造成了肋骨和手腕处骨折
fracturing a rib and very nearly his wrist?
-是的  -谢谢
- Yes. - Thank you.
没有更多问题了
No further questions.
你可以下来了
You can step down now.
我建议进行短暂的休庭
I'm going to suggest that we take a brief recess here
我要审核所有的证词和材料
while I review all of the testimony and materials.
我  我不能
I... I... I can't.
-抱歉没听清  -我不能
- Excuse me? - I can't!
我不能这样做  我  我以为我可以  但是我
I... I can't do this. I... I thought I could, but I... I just...
我没看到任何事  我只是按照你说的做
I didn't see anything. I'm only saying what you told me to say.
很抱歉  但是我不能继续了
I'm sorry, but I can't do this anymore.
丹尼深爱Eve  他不可能伤害她的父亲
I know that Denny loved Eve too much to ever hurt her father.
反对  证人明显是在臆测
Objection. The witness is clearly speculating.
律师  这可是你的证人
It's your witness, counselor.
他们撤诉了
They dropped the charges.
所有指控  一笔勾销
All of it. Tossed out.
你赢了丹尼  都结束了
You did it, Denny. It's over, man.
他做到了  丹尼冒的险得到了回报
He'd done it. Denny's risk had paid off.
如果一个车手勇敢到给自己制造挑战
If a driver has the courage to create his own conditions...
下雨也不过就是个天气
then the rain is simply rain.
爸爸
Daddy!
-我想你了  -我也好想你
- I missed you. - Oh, I missed you.
佐伊又是我们的了
Zoe was ours again.
丹尼赢回了她  那是一场世纪性胜利
Denny had won her back, and it was a victory for the ages.
你好
Hello.
丹尼  我是卢卡 Pantoni  来回你电话了
Denny, this is Luca Pantoni returning your call.
卢卡  是我  你好  谢谢你打回来
Luca, yes, hi. Thank you for calling me back.
我想告诉你
I... I wanted to let you know
那件让我无法出国的麻烦事
that the issues keeping me in the States
已经解决了
have been resolved.
我都能想象到
I could just picture him
他站在一栋大别墅的阳台上
on the terrace of some magnificent villa.
从你的声音里能听出
I can tell by your voice
-事情解决得很顺利  -没错  先生
- they were resolved to your satisfaction. - Yes, sir.
我  我在想
And I... I was wondering if the job
您之前想聘用我的那份工作
that you'd offered me earlier,
-还是我的吗  -是的
- if that was still available? - It is.
那么我和我女儿  还有我们的狗恩佐
Then my daughter and I, and our dog Enzo,
非常乐意去马拉内罗加入你们
would very much like to join you in Maranello.
你的狗叫恩佐
Your dog's name is Enzo?
是的  他是个天生的赛车手
Yeah, he's a race car driver at heart.
我会让助理安排好一切
Okay, I will have my assistant make all the arrangements.
欢迎来到法拉利
Welcome to Ferrari.
下次再聊  丹尼
We will talk again soon, Denny.
再见
Ciao.
是什么呀  佐伊
What is it, Zoe?
这个聚会真棒  看看这些礼物  真好
This is a great party, look at these gifts, it's great.
-蛋糕不错  丹尼  -好可爱
- Nice cake, Denny. - So cute.
祝你有个童话般的生日
"Wishing for you a fairy tale birthday."
收到什么了
What'd you get?
-爸  你看  -真酷
- Daddy, look! - Oh, cool.
我不是
I don't...
如果你想让我离开  我可以
If you want me to go, I could...
-奶奶  -我的宝贝
- Grandma! - Hi, sweetheart.
我可不会这么轻易原谅
I might not have been as forgiving.
但是丹尼要为佐伊着想
But Denny had Zoe to think about.
我经常听人说  要做更好的人
I'd often heard the expression "To be the better man."
爷爷
Grandpa!
不过我不认识比丹尼更好的人了
Well, I knew no better man than Denny.
九岁是个大日子
Big number nine.
好了
All right.
-准备好了吗  -各就各位  预备
- You ready? - Ready, steady
出发
Go
-生日快乐  -谢谢爸爸
- Happy birthday. - Thanks, Daddy.
-谁要吃蛋糕  -我
- Okay, who wants cake? - Me!
奶奶能不能帮我一下
Grandma, will you help me with this?
从厨房拿把刀过来
Okay, grab a knife from the kitchen, please.
有时我的一生看起来已经过了很久
Sometimes my life seems like it has been so long
同时又如此短暂
and so short at the same time.
我觉得自己好像活了几辈子
I feel as if I've lived for an eternity.
Enz
Yo, Enz!
但似乎又像是时光从未流逝一般
And yet it's as if no time has passed at all.
恩佐
Enzo?
我听出了他的担忧
I hear the worry in his voice.
发生了什么  老伙计
What happened, pal?
-恩佐  -我能闻出他这一天所经历的
- Oh, Enz. - I can smell the day on him.
机油  汽油和烤鸡
Motor oil and gasoline and roast chicken.
你能站起来吗  兄弟
Can you get up, bud?
我在电视上看过一部有关蒙古的纪录片
I saw a documentary about Mongolia on TV once.
在蒙古  一条狗死之后
In Mongolia, when a dog dies,
他会被埋在高高的山顶
he is buried high in the hills,
所以没有人会践踏他的坟墓
so people cannot walk on his grave.
老兄  我在这  我就在这陪你
I'm here, buddy. I'm right here.
主人会在狗的耳边轻声许愿
His master whispers into the dog's ears
希望他的狗在来生可以转世为人
his wishes that in his next life the dog will return as a man.
他们说  不是所有狗都能转世
Not all dogs return as men, they say.
只有那些准备好了的才行
Only those who are ready.
我帮你起来
Let's get you up.
我准备好了
I am ready.
我知道死亡不是终点  Eve告诉过我
I know death is not the end. Eve told me so.
我也相信她
And I believe her.
当我回到这世界上  被人从子宫拽出来时
When I return to this world, I will practically be an adult
我估计已经是个成年人了
the moment I am plucked from the womb
毕竟我都准备这么久了
with all the preparation I have done.
-你在这儿呢  -我会走在人群中
- There he is. - I will walk among my fellow men,
用我小巧的舌头舔着嘴唇
lick my lips with my small dexterous tongue
用力地去握手
and shake hands with a firm grasp.
我的恩佐
There's my Enzo.
然后我会教给人们我所知道的一切
And I will teach people all that I know.
我所学到的一切
All that I have learned.
-好点了吗  -我很好  丹尼
- You okay now? - I'm fine, Denny. I am
你一直都陪伴着我
You've always been with me.
你一直都会是我的恩佐
You've always been my Enzo.
第一次见面  我就知道我们注定在一起
First time I saw you, I knew we were supposed to be together.
我爱你
I love you, boy.
-你怎么在这  -我想咱们可以一起去赛道
- What are you doing here? - I thought we'd go to the track.
我有个惊喜给恩佐
'Cause I have a surprise for Enzo.
谢谢你的安排  唐
Thanks for arranging this, Don.
我们不会占用太久
We won't be out long.
慢慢来  跑道都是你的
Take your time. Track's all yours.
-玩得开心  -谢谢你  宝贝
- Have fun. - Thank you, sweetheart.
没有太紧吧
Not too tight?
准备好了吗
You ready?
很好
All right.
车手们  发动引擎
Drivers, start your engines.
我从来都没觉得自己如此特殊
I have never ever felt so special.
你成功了  老兄
You did it, man.
刹车热了  轮胎也热了
Brakes are warm, tires are warm.
我们来一圈激烈的怎么样
What do you say we try a hot lap, huh?
我真想一直待在这里
I'd like to stay out here forever.
永远陪伴着他们
Stay with them forever.
我们这一圈要加速了  你没意见吧
We're gonna take this one at speed. You okay?
我想看一眼他们在马拉内罗的生活
I wish I could glimpse what awaits them in Maranello.
丹尼会成为一名优秀的法拉利车手
Denny will be a wonderful driver for Ferrari.
优秀到有一天他们会把他从排位上拿下
So wonderful that one day they will pluck him from the ranks
给他一次加入F1队伍的机会
to give him a tryout for their Formula One team.
他会说  走着瞧吧  我多想看到那一天
"Try me," he'll say. I'd like to see that.
恩佐
Enzo!
但是我们不可能得到全部想要的
But we can't have everything we want.
况且  好的车手不会沉溺于过往或将来
Besides, the best drivers don't dwell on the future or the past.
最好的车手只着眼于当下
The best drivers focus only on the present.
你一直都是我的好伙伴
You've been a good friend.
非常非常好的伙伴
A very good friend!
最好的伙伴
The best of friends.
过来
Come here.
我们马上就会回家了
We'll be heading home soon.
但此时此刻  我只想再来一圈
But for now, all I want is one more lap.
就一圈
Just one more.
我要叫几声让他知道
I'll bark again so he knows.
快点  丹尼  再快点
Faster, Denny. Faster!
八年后
Mugello  意大利
爸
Dad!
有人想见见你
There's some people who want to meet you.
来吧  他们可是铁粉
Come on, they're big fans.
我相信你会很喜欢他们
I think you'd really like them.
你说了算
You're the boss.
意大利语
我们是你忠实的车迷
We are your biggest fans.
你女儿说你不会介意的
Your daughter said that you would not mind.
当然不会
No, of course not.
我的儿子经常提起你
My son, he talks about you always.
他参加微型赛车比赛  他很出色
He races the go-carts. He's very good.
好  很好
Bene. Va bene.
-可以麻烦你在画册上签名吗  -没问题
- Could you please sign the program? - Sure.
我们明天会在内场看比赛
We are going to watch the race from the infield tomorrow.
你叫什么名字
Come ti chiami?
恩佐
Enzo.
Enzo?
我叫恩佐
My name is Enzo.
他想成为冠军  像你一样
He wants to be a champion. Like you.
对不起
Mi scusi.
你儿子让我想起了一位老朋友
Your son reminds me of an old friend of mine.
我在马拉内罗的电话
My phone number in Maranello.
当你觉得他准备好了  打给我
When you think your son is ready, give me a call.
我保证他会得到专业的指导
I'll make sure he gets proper instruction.
谢谢  他  他无时无刻不在谈论你
Grazie. He... he talks about you always.
他说你是史上最好的车手
He says that you are the greatest driver ever.
比塞纳还要出色
Better even than Senna.
埃尔顿·塞纳
三届F1世界冠军得主  被称为车神塞纳
他天生就是个赛车手
Well, he's a racecar driver at heart.
-谢谢你  万分感谢  -谢谢
- Graziel! Grazie millet! - Graziel
不客气
Prego.
走吧
Come on.